<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hash-cracking on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/hash-cracking/</link><description>Recent content in hash-cracking on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/hash-cracking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Driver</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine contains a website with default credentials authentication and a file upload. Here we can upload an SCF to capture the user&amp;rsquo;s NTLMv2 hash and crack it. Then we can exploit PrintNightmare. Windows basic exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>GoodGames</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to SQL injection where we can extract a password to access an internal website that is vulnerable to SSTI. Then, we get access to a Docker container that mounts a directory from the machine, so that we can abuse it to escalate privileges. Basic web exploitation skills and Docker breakout techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>Bolt</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has several virtual hosts and a Docker image that contains a lot of information needed to exploit the websites. There is an SSTI vulnerability between two websites interaction. Then we can extract a PGP private key from Google Chrome cache and decrypt a message. Deep knowledge about Docker and basic web exploitation skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Previse</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a webpage vulnerable to command injection after bypassing redirects and managing to register a new account. After that, a hash must be cracked to login as a low privileged user and perform a PATH hijacking using sudo. Common web pentesting and Burp Suite skills, as well as common privilege escalation techniques are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a custom Go program to automate the foothold process</description></item><item><title>Writer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to SQL injection. This allows to read the source code of the server and find a vulnerability. Then some command injection techniques to escalate privileges. Some scripting for automating a SQLi exploit, SMB, SMTP and Cron tasks are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses custom Python scripts for SQLi and for the foothold</description></item><item><title>Intelligence</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intelligence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intelligence/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Medium machine. This machine presents an Active Directory (AD) environment to perform user enumeration, network poisoning and a Silver Ticket attack. Some scripting, DNS operations, AD attacks and BloodHound basics are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Go script to fuzz for files in a web server</description></item><item><title>Forest</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forest/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine presents an Active Directory (AD) environment to perform MS RPC enumeration, AS-REProasting, password decrypting, DCSync and Pass the Hash. Basic AD enumeration and exploitation skills, as well as BloodHound knowledge, are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Active</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/active/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/active/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine presents an Active Directory (AD) environment to perform SMB enumeration, password decrypting and Kerberoasting. Basic AD enumeration and exploitation skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>