<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hash-cracking on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/hash-cracking/</link><description>Recent content in hash-cracking on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/hash-cracking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RainyDay</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rainyday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rainyday/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website vulnerable to user enumeration. Then we can use brute force a user&amp;rsquo;s password and run containers. Using a container we can access an internal website that has an API that shows sensitive information using Type Juggling and has a feature for matching regular expressions on given files, so that we can read source code and get the secret key for Flask. Then, we can forge a session for user &lt;code>jack&lt;/code> and find out that the Docker containers allow to access process information from the machine, and we can read the private SSH key of this user. Next, we can run a custom Python interpreter and escape the sandbox to get a shell as &lt;code>jack_adm&lt;/code>. Finally, we have a tool to generate hashes with &lt;code>bcrypt&lt;/code>, and we need to exploit a limitation of &lt;code>bcrypt&lt;/code> to extract a secret pepper string and then crack &lt;code>root&lt;/code>&amp;rsquo;s hash in order to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Shoppy</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection. Using this vulnerability, we can bypass authentication and list some hashed passwords that can be cracked. Then, we enumerate subdomains and find a MatterMost application in which we can access and find credentials for SSH in the machine. The first user is able to run a custom ELF binary that shows more credentials when using a specific master password. Finally, we can escalate privileges because the second user belongs to group docker</description></item><item><title>Health</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/health/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/health/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a webhook functionality that seems vulnerable to Server-Side Request Forgery. After trying some bypasses, we see that the SSRF attack can be performed using a redirection. Internally, there is an outdated Gogs version that is vulnerable to SQLi. Once found a payload to extract password hashes from the database, we can obtain and crack the hashes from the remote Gogs instance with SQLi through SSRF. Then, we can connect with SSH and find out that we can enter local paths in the database to read files from the server as root. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform the SSRF attack and another Go program to crack Gogs hashes</description></item><item><title>Shared</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shared/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shared/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has an e-commerce store that is vulnerable to SQLi. With this vulnerability we can get a hashed password which is reused for SSH. There is another user that runs ipython periodically, so we can inject a configuration file to execute commands. The second user is able to use a binary compiled in Go that connects to Redis. A binary analysis reveals the password, so we can connect to Redis and exploit a CVE to run Lua code, escape from the sandbox and execute system commands as root</description></item><item><title>Scanned</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/scanned/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/scanned/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine has a website that is able to analyze malware binaries. Analyzing the sandbox C code, we notice that we can use a log file to exfiltrate information through the web server report, and also abuse a misconfiguration to escape from chroot. Then, we can read a SQLite database file and extract a hashed password, which is reused for SSH. Once inside the machine, we are able to run a SUID binary from inside the sandbox and copy a malicious shared library so that the SUID binary runs Bash as root. Deep knowledge about Linux, programming in C and Bash, code audit experience and escaping techniques is needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script with an embedded C program to list directories and read files from the server and also a Go program to crack a hashed password</description></item><item><title>Timelapse</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timelapse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timelapse/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine presents an Active Directory (AD) environment where we can find an encrypted ZIP file in SMB. We can crack the password and find a PFX file holding public and private keys for WinRM. Again we can crack the password and extract the keys to connect to the machine. There is a PowerShell history where we find a password for a LAPS reader member, which will tell us the password for Administrator. Basic Windows exploitation techniques and enumeration are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Acute</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/acute/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/acute/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Hard machine. This machine exposes a website where we can find a Word document with useful information and some usernames. There is a PowerShell Web Access where we can access using a default credential and extract another password from a screenshot. There is an Active Directory domain controller where we can execute commands as other users. We will be able to connect to the first machine and dump NTLM hashes and finally become domain administrator. Deep knowledge on PowerShell commands and basic Windows and Active Directory exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Undetected</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/undetected/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/undetected/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website in PHP with a third-party dependency that is vulnerable to RCE. The machine has already been compromised and has some backdoors and exploits that need to be detected and analyzed using reverse engineering techniques</description></item><item><title>Overflow</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Padding Oracle Attack and Bit Flipper Attack to login as admin and also vulnerable to SQLi by a CMS. There is another subdomain that runs a version of exiftool that has an RCE vulnerability. Once in the machine, lateral movements are relatively easy and privilege escalation consists of reversing and exploiting a Buffer Overflow vulnerability on a SUID binary. Deep knowledge on web exploitation, cryptography and binary exploitation are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform a Bit Flipper Attack and a Ruby script to exploit SQLi</description></item><item><title>Shibboleth</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shibboleth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shibboleth/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a vulnerable IPMI service where we can find a password that is reused for a Zabbix control panel. Here we can enter and get access to the machine. Next, we find a vulnerable version for MariaDB which leads to RCE as root. Good enumeration and pentesting methodology are needed in order to comprimise this machine</description></item><item><title>Driver</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine contains a website with default credentials authentication and a file upload. Here we can upload an SCF to capture the user&amp;rsquo;s NTLMv2 hash and crack it. Then we can exploit PrintNightmare. Windows basic exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>GoodGames</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to SQL injection where we can extract a password to access an internal website that is vulnerable to SSTI. Then, we get access to a Docker container that mounts a directory from the machine, so that we can abuse it to escalate privileges. Basic web exploitation skills and Docker breakout techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>Bolt</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has several virtual hosts and a Docker image that contains a lot of information needed to exploit the websites. There is an SSTI vulnerability between two websites interaction. Then we can extract a PGP private key from Google Chrome cache and decrypt a message. Deep knowledge about Docker and basic web exploitation skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Previse</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a webpage vulnerable to command injection after bypassing redirects and managing to register a new account. After that, a hash must be cracked to login as a low privileged user and perform a PATH hijacking using sudo. Common web pentesting and Burp Suite skills, as well as common privilege escalation techniques are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a custom Go program to automate the foothold process</description></item><item><title>Writer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to SQL injection. This allows to read the source code of the server and find a vulnerability. Then some command injection techniques to escalate privileges. Some scripting for automating a SQLi exploit, SMB, SMTP and Cron tasks are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses custom Python scripts for SQLi and for the foothold</description></item><item><title>Intelligence</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intelligence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intelligence/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Medium machine. This machine presents an Active Directory (AD) environment to perform user enumeration, network poisoning and a Silver Ticket attack. Some scripting, DNS operations, AD attacks and BloodHound basics are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Go script to fuzz for files in a web server</description></item><item><title>Forest</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forest/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine presents an Active Directory (AD) environment to perform MS RPC enumeration, AS-REP Roasting, password decrypting, DCSync and Pass the Hash. Basic AD enumeration and exploitation skills, as well as BloodHound knowledge, are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Active</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/active/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/active/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine presents an Active Directory (AD) environment to perform SMB enumeration, password decrypting and Kerberoasting. Basic AD enumeration and exploitation skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>