<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Perl on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/perl/</link><description>Recent content in Perl on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 18:56:03 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/perl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Investigation</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/investigation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/investigation/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that allows to analyze image file metadata with &lt;code>exiftool&lt;/code>. However, the version is vulnerable to command injection and can be used to access the system. Then, we find some Windows event logs and a plaintext password as username, probably a mistake. After that, we gain access as another user that is able to execute a binary with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which behind the scenes runs a Perl script that leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Pikaboo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine uses nginx and Apache web servers with a misconfiguration that derives in directory path traversal and afterwards in local file inclusion. There are credentials for FTP in LDAP and a Cron job that is vulnerable to command injection. Web enumeration, knowledge about nginx and LDAP, file inclusion techniques and command injection tricks are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>Nunchucks</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nunchucks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nunchucks/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a webpage vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI) and system capabilities set, but with some protections. Knowledge about Node.js templates and Perl are needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>