<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Crypto on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/crypto/</link><description>Recent content in Crypto on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 17:42:50 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/crypto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sandworm</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sandworm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sandworm/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that allows to encrypt, decrypt and verify signatures using PGP. The website is vulnerable to SSTI in Flask, which is the way to access the machine as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code>. However, this environment is limited due to &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code>, but we are able to find a plaintext password to login as &lt;code>silentobserver&lt;/code> in SSH. As this user, we are able to modify a Rust project that is used in another Rust project that runs periodically as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code>. With this power, we can get access as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code> again, but outside &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code>. Finally, since &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code> is a SUID binary, we can use a public exploit to become &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intentions/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website with an API that is vulnerable to second-order SQLi. Then, there is an authentication mechanism that just requires the password hash, so we can take a hash from the dumped database and log in as an administrator. Then, there is a vulnerability involving PHP and ImageMagick that leads to RCE. Once in the machine, we can pivot to user &lt;code>greg&lt;/code> by analyzing a Git repository and finding plaintext credentials. After that, we are allowed to run a custom binary that hashes a given length of a file and compares the result with a set of pre-computed MD5 hashes. This binary has a capability that allows to read files as &lt;code>root&lt;/code>, which can be used to extract all the contents of any file after automating the process, which allows to read an SSH private key for &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>RainyDay</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rainyday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rainyday/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website vulnerable to user enumeration. Then we can use brute force a user&amp;rsquo;s password and run containers. Using a container we can access an internal website that has an API that shows sensitive information using Type Juggling and has a feature for matching regular expressions on given files, so that we can read source code and get the secret key for Flask. Then, we can forge a session for user &lt;code>jack&lt;/code> and find out that the Docker containers allow to access process information from the machine, and we can read the private SSH key of this user. Next, we can run a custom Python interpreter and escape the sandbox to get a shell as &lt;code>jack_adm&lt;/code>. Finally, we have a tool to generate hashes with &lt;code>bcrypt&lt;/code>, and we need to exploit a limitation of &lt;code>bcrypt&lt;/code> to extract a secret pepper string and then crack &lt;code>root&lt;/code>&amp;rsquo;s hash in order to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Undetected</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/undetected/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/undetected/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website in PHP with a third-party dependency that is vulnerable to RCE. The machine has already been compromised and has some backdoors and exploits that need to be detected and analyzed using reverse engineering techniques</description></item><item><title>Overflow</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Padding Oracle Attack and Bit Flipper Attack to login as admin and also vulnerable to SQLi by a CMS. There is another subdomain that runs a version of exiftool that has an RCE vulnerability. Once in the machine, lateral movements are relatively easy and privilege escalation consists of reversing and exploiting a Buffer Overflow vulnerability on a SUID binary. Deep knowledge on web exploitation, cryptography and binary exploitation are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform a Bit Flipper Attack and a Ruby script to exploit SQLi</description></item><item><title>Ransom</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ransom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ransom/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a Laravel website with a login form that is vulnerable to Type Juggling. After that we find a encrypted ZIP file and we can perform a known plaintext attack to extract the files. The password expected for the login form is reused for the root user. Basic knowledge about web pentesting on PHP and knowledge about ZIP files is required in order to comprimise this machine</description></item><item><title>Hancliffe</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/hancliffe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/hancliffe/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Hard machine. This machine contains a webpage that hides a Nuxeo Java application vulnerable to SSTI by breaking nginx parser logic. Then we find access the machine and find an application that has a public exploit to access as another user. After that, we extract Firefox credentials and use a password generator to login as another user and find a custom Windows PE. Having reversed the binary to obtain the expected credentials, we find a Buffer Overflow vulnerability that must be exploited via Socket Reuse to access as Administrator</description></item></channel></rss>