<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>python on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in python on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unicode</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses JWT tokens with JWKS and JKU that can be forged to arrive to a directory path traversal vulnerability that can be exploited using some Unicode bypassing. After that, there is a Python compiled binary that can be run with sudo and uses curl behind the hoods. Some JWT knowledge, path traversal and command injection bypassing techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to exploit a directory path traversal using JWT with JWKS</description></item><item><title>Backend</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backend/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backend/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has an API where we can create a new account after some exploration. Then we can find some documentation in Swagger format where we see an endpoint to execute commands and to read files from the server. We must find the secret key used to sign JWT tokens in order to create a valid token to execute commands. Knowledge on JWT tokens and API enumeration are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Forge</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forge/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a Server-Side Request Forgery (SSRF) vulnerability from a subdomain to an FTP server. After that, there are sudo permissions to run a Python script with a debugger. Basic web pentesting bypassing techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to exploit the SSRF</description></item><item><title>BountyHunter</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bountyhunter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bountyhunter/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and that has sudo permissions configured. Some knowledge about XXE, PHP and Python is needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to read files from the server exploiting XXE</description></item></channel></rss>