<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>static-code-analysis on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/static-code-analysis/</link><description>Recent content in static-code-analysis on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/static-code-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Secret</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy Machine. This machine contains an API that uses JWT tokens for authentication. We can download the proyect and discover that it is a Git repository, so that we can see the secret key in previous commits and exploit a command injection vulnerability. There is a SUID binary that reads files as root although it only shows some statistics of the file, but we are able to kill the process and read the coredump. Web exploitation techniques, Git enumeration and knowledge about Linux processes are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Devzat</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/devzat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/devzat/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains chat service over SSH and a hidden web subdomain vulnerable to command injection. Then we can access the machine and exploit a vulnerable version of InluxDB to extract the password for another user. This user has permissions to see a development project for the SSH chat that allows to read arbitrary files from the server</description></item><item><title>Epsilon</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that exposes Git repository with secrets in old commits. There is a website that needs a valid JWT token in order to exploit an SSTI vulnerability. The secret for the JWT tokens is stored in an AWS Lambda function. Then, there is a Cron job that can be exploited using symlinks to gain arbitrary read. Knowledge about Git, JWT, SSTI and AWS Lambda, as well as Cron job exploitation, is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Writer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to SQL injection. This allows to read the source code of the server and find a vulnerability. Then some command injection techniques to escalate privileges. Some scripting for automating a SQLi exploit, SMB, SMTP and Cron tasks are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses custom Python scripts for SQLi and for the foothold</description></item><item><title>Union</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains Union-based SQL injection (SQLi) and command injection vulnerabilities. Some SQLi bypassing techniques and source code analysis skills are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Java program to automate a SQLi attack</description></item></channel></rss>