<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Log-Poisoning on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/log-poisoning/</link><description>Recent content in Log-Poisoning on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 02:13:27 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/log-poisoning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RedPanda</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/redpanda/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/redpanda/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application built with Spring Boot that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection with a particular format. After that, in order to escalate privileges, we must analyze a Java program, enter some malicious metadata in a JPEG image, add an XML External Entity into a controlled XML file, break a log parser logic and finally wait for root to process the XML file and read its private SSH key</description></item><item><title>Pikaboo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine uses nginx and Apache web servers with a misconfiguration that derives in directory path traversal and afterwards in local file inclusion. There are credentials for FTP in LDAP and a Cron job that is vulnerable to command injection. Web enumeration, knowledge about nginx and LDAP, file inclusion techniques and command injection tricks are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>LogForge</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses Log4j in a Tomcat server that is vulnerable to JNDI lookup. Then there is an FTP server made in Java that also uses Log4j, but this time it is only vulnerable to information disclosure. Knowlegde about Log4j exploitation, Tomcat, FTP and Wireshark are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>