<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Type-Juggling on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/type-juggling/</link><description>Recent content in Type-Juggling on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 02:13:27 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/type-juggling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vessel</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/vessel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/vessel/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website that exposes a Git repository. Here we can read the source code of the web application and find out a way to bypass authentication in MySQL with Type Juggling. Then, we find another subdomain that has a public exploit to get RCE. After that, we discover a password generator tool that can be reverse-engineered to generate multiple passwords and crack a password-protected PDF document. Then, we get access via SSH and see that we can use &lt;code>sysctl&lt;/code> as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> with &lt;code>pinns&lt;/code> as SUID binary. With this, we can modify the kernel configuration to run an arbitrary script with a program crashes, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>RainyDay</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rainyday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rainyday/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website vulnerable to user enumeration. Then we can use brute force a user&amp;rsquo;s password and run containers. Using a container we can access an internal website that has an API that shows sensitive information using Type Juggling and has a feature for matching regular expressions on given files, so that we can read source code and get the secret key for Flask. Then, we can forge a session for user &lt;code>jack&lt;/code> and find out that the Docker containers allow to access process information from the machine, and we can read the private SSH key of this user. Next, we can run a custom Python interpreter and escape the sandbox to get a shell as &lt;code>jack_adm&lt;/code>. Finally, we have a tool to generate hashes with &lt;code>bcrypt&lt;/code>, and we need to exploit a limitation of &lt;code>bcrypt&lt;/code> to extract a secret pepper string and then crack &lt;code>root&lt;/code>&amp;rsquo;s hash in order to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Timing</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP web application that is vulnerable to user enumeration, LFI, Type Juggling and SQLi, apart from some other bugs and misconfigurations. After reading the PHP source code, we find a way to upload a PHP web shell and get RCE. After that, we find a password inside a Git repository and access via SSH. Then, we can run a JAR file using sudo that downloads files as root, and we can use a symlink to write an authorized SSH key for root</description></item><item><title>Altered</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/altered/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/altered/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a PHP website vulnerable to user enumeration. Then we can use brute force on a PIN to reset a password after bypassing rate limits and exploit SQLi and Type Juggling. After that, we see that the Linux kernel is vulnerable to DirtyPipe. Advanced web exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Ruby script to find the valid PIN</description></item><item><title>Ransom</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ransom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ransom/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a Laravel website with a login form that is vulnerable to Type Juggling. After that we find a encrypted ZIP file and we can perform a known plaintext attack to extract the files. The password expected for the login form is reused for the root user. Basic knowledge about web pentesting on PHP and knowledge about ZIP files is required in order to comprimise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>