<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OSINT on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/</link><description>Recent content in OSINT on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Block Hunt3r</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/block-hunt3r/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/block-hunt3r/</guid><description>We are told that someone has been uploading images to Görli testnet (an Ethereum Blockchain) between 2020-07-30 and 2020-08-01. We need to find one image that contains the flag.
Görli testnet To interact with Görli we need to go to https://goerli.etherscan.io. We can find the range of block numbers within the dates specified manually going to https://goerli.etherscan.io/blocks/&amp;lt;number&amp;gt;. Poking around with the website, we find that https://goerli.etherscan.io/block/3134050 is the first block of the range and https://goerli.</description></item><item><title>Easy Phish</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/easy-phish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/easy-phish/</guid><description>We have this challenge description:
Customers of secure-startup.com have been recieving some very convincing phishing emails, can you figure out why?
DNS enumeration First, we can try to enumerate secure-startup.com using several DNS records (more information here) and dig.
The TXT record outputs a part of the flag:
$ dig secure-startup.com TXT ; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.10.6 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; secure-startup.com TXT ;; global options: +cmd ;; Got answer: ;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 48771 ;; flags: qr rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 1, AUTHORITY: 0, ADDITIONAL: 1 ;; OPT PSEUDOSECTION: ; EDNS: version: 0, flags:; udp: 4096 ;; QUESTION SECTION: ;secure-startup.</description></item><item><title>ID Exposed</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/id-exposed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/id-exposed/</guid><description>We have this challenge description:
We are looking for Sara Medson Cruz&amp;rsquo;s last location, where she left a message. We need to find out what this message is! We only have her email: saramedsoncruz@gmail.com
Google Maps Since the email address is from Gmail, we can try to find visited locations in Google Maps. Maybe the user searched a place or commented something about a place.
For that, we will need to write an email (without sending it).</description></item><item><title>Infiltration</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/infiltration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/infiltration/</guid><description>We have this challenge description:
Can you find something to help you break into the company &amp;lsquo;Evil Corp LLC&amp;rsquo;. Recon social media sites to see if you can find any useful information.
LinkedIn We can start by entering the name of the company in a search engine:
The first thing that pops out is LinkedIn:
Here we have a fake flag. We can examine the company&amp;rsquo;s website, but there&amp;rsquo;s nothing interesting:</description></item><item><title>Missing in Action</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/missing-in-action/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/missing-in-action/</guid><description>We have this challenge description:
Roland Sanchez from Birmingham, UK is missing. The family are convinced he was kidnapped on a business trip. Can you help?
LinkedIn We can start by entering some key words in a search engine:
The first thing that pops out is LinkedIn:
Here we have the company&amp;rsquo;s name: Egotistical Bank.
Twitter If we enter the company&amp;rsquo;s name in a search engine, the first thing that pops out is Twitter:</description></item><item><title>Money Flowz</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/money-flowz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/money-flowz/</guid><description>We have this challenge description:
Frank Vitalik is a hustler, can you figure out where the money flows?
Reddit First, we can search for the name we have on a search engine:
We are directed to Reddit. Here we can see some posts from Frank Vitalik with some scams:
And this one is a scam to get &amp;ldquo;free coinz&amp;rdquo;:
The next thing to analyze is an Ethereum wallet address.
Ethereum enumeration Especifically, we must go to an Ethereum testnet called Ropsten:</description></item><item><title>Monstrosity</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/monstrosity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/ctf/htb-challenges/osint/monstrosity/</guid><description>We have this challenge description:
The following social media account is associated with a widespread banking trojan that is silently infecting an increasing number of victims the past few days. There is intense interaction with the aforementioned account right before the self-decryption function of the malicious executable. Investigators around the world are trying to reverse engineer this specific part of the malware with no success so far. Search the account for potential clues that could prove useful.</description></item></channel></rss>