<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lfi on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/lfi/</link><description>Recent content in Lfi on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:41:59 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/lfi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>UpDown</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/updown/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/updown/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that has a development directory and exposes a Git repository. Using this, we can find some functionality that is hidden except for developers and can be abused to get RCE after planning the attack and bypassing &lt;code>disable_functions&lt;/code> in PHP. In the machine, there&amp;rsquo;s a SUID binary compiled out of a Python script, which can be abused with a library hijacking attack. Finally, the developer user is able to run &lt;code>easy_install&lt;/code> with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Trick</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/trick/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/trick/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a DNS service that is vulnerable to a Domain Zone Transfer attack and leaks a subdomain. Here we can bypass authentication with SQLi and exploit an LFI. Both vulnerabilities can be chained to get access to the machine. Then, we find another subdomain that is again vulnerable to LFI, and we can leak a user&amp;rsquo;s SSH private key. This user is able to restart fail2ban with sudo and modify configuration files</description></item><item><title>Timing</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP web application that is vulnerable to user enumeration, LFI, Type Juggling and SQLi, apart from some other bugs and misconfigurations. After reading the PHP source code, we find a way to upload a PHP web shell and get RCE. After that, we find a password inside a Git repository and access via SSH. Then, we can run a JAR file using sudo that downloads files as root, and we can use a symlink to write an authorized SSH key for root</description></item><item><title>Pikaboo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine uses nginx and Apache web servers with a misconfiguration that derives in directory path traversal and afterwards in local file inclusion. There are credentials for FTP in LDAP and a Cron job that is vulnerable to command injection. Web enumeration, knowledge about nginx and LDAP, file inclusion techniques and command injection tricks are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item></channel></rss>