<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bloodhound on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/bloodhound/</link><description>Recent content in bloodhound on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/bloodhound/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Escape</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/escape/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/escape/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Medium machine. This machine shares a PDF file via SMB and shows credentials to access Microsoft SQL Server. Here, we are able to use &lt;code>xp_dirtree&lt;/code> to list an external SMB share and crack the NTLMv2 hash. After that, we can access the machine, read the logs of Microsoft SQL Server and discover the password of another user. Then, we find some vulnerable certificate templates that can be abused to authenticate as &lt;code>Administrator&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Intelligence</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intelligence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intelligence/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Medium machine. This machine presents an Active Directory (AD) environment to perform user enumeration, network poisoning and a Silver Ticket attack. Some scripting, DNS operations, AD attacks and BloodHound basics are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Go script to fuzz for files in a web server</description></item><item><title>Forest</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forest/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine presents an Active Directory (AD) environment to perform MS RPC enumeration, AS-REP Roasting, password decrypting, DCSync and Pass the Hash. Basic AD enumeration and exploitation skills, as well as BloodHound knowledge, are needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>