<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Xxe on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/xxe/</link><description>Recent content in Xxe on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:41:59 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/xxe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MetaTwo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/metatwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/metatwo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a WordPress website that uses a plugin that is vulnerable to SQLi. Then we can get password hashes and crack one of them to get access to the WordPress dashboard. The version of WordPress is vulnerable to out-of-band XXE using a WAV file that allows to read files from the server. Using this vulnerability, we can find plaintext credentials for FTP. In this service we have another PHP file with more plaintext credentials that are valid for SSH. Once inside the machine, we can see some PGP keys and messages that can be decrypted to find the password for &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>RedPanda</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/redpanda/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/redpanda/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application built with Spring Boot that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection with a particular format. After that, in order to escalate privileges, we must analyze a Java program, enter some malicious metadata in a JPEG image, add an XML External Entity into a controlled XML file, break a log parser logic and finally wait for root to process the XML file and read its private SSH key</description></item><item><title>NodeBlog</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a blog that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection, then to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and finally to insecure deserialization to get Remote Code Execution. Advanced web pentesting techniques and scripting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses custom scripts in Bash, Python and Node.js to exploit all vulnerabilities</description></item><item><title>BountyHunter</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bountyhunter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bountyhunter/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and that has sudo permissions configured. Some knowledge about XXE, PHP and Python is needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to read files from the server exploiting XXE</description></item><item><title>Spider</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI) in two fields and SQL injection (SQLi), and an internal website that is vulnerable to XML External Entity (XXE) injection. Advanced knowledge on SSTI and bypassing techniques, SQLi, XXE and port forwarding skills are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a Python script to exploit SSTI and a Bash script to read file using XXE</description></item></channel></rss>