<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ssti on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/ssti/</link><description>Recent content in ssti on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/ssti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RedPanda</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/redpanda/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/redpanda/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application built with Spring Boot that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection with a particular format. After that, in order to escalate privileges, we must analyze a Java program, enter some malicious metadata in a JPEG image, add an XML External Entity into a controlled XML file, break a log parser logic and finally wait for root to process the XML file and read its private SSH key</description></item><item><title>Late</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/late/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/late/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a Flask web application that extracts text from images and renders them, being vulnerable to SSTI. Then there is a PAM configured for SSH with relative paths that can be abused because of some privileges to ovewrite executables. Basic web exploitation and Linux enumeration skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Catch</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine offers an APK file that contains hard-coded authentication tokens for some services exposed by the machine. One of the tokens can be used to enumerate a Let&amp;rsquo;s Chat application using its API and get credentials for Cachet. This service is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection in PHP and we can get more credentials to access via SSH. The machine has a Cron job configured to analyze APK files using a Bash script that is vulnerable to command injection, so we need to upload a maliciously crafted APK file to exploit it and become root</description></item><item><title>Hancliffe</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/hancliffe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/hancliffe/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Hard machine. This machine contains a webpage that hides a Nuxeo Java application vulnerable to SSTI by breaking nginx parser logic. Then we find access the machine and find an application that has a public exploit to access as another user. After that, we extract Firefox credentials and use a password generator to login as another user and find a custom Windows PE. Having reversed the binary to obtain the expected credentials, we find a Buffer Overflow vulnerability that must be exploited via Socket Reuse to access as Administrator</description></item><item><title>GoodGames</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to SQL injection where we can extract a password to access an internal website that is vulnerable to SSTI. Then, we get access to a Docker container that mounts a directory from the machine, so that we can abuse it to escalate privileges. Basic web exploitation skills and Docker breakout techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>Bolt</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has several virtual hosts and a Docker image that contains a lot of information needed to exploit the websites. There is an SSTI vulnerability between two websites interaction. Then we can extract a PGP private key from Google Chrome cache and decrypt a message. Deep knowledge about Docker and basic web exploitation skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Epsilon</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that exposes Git repository with secrets in old commits. There is a website that needs a valid JWT token in order to exploit an SSTI vulnerability. The secret for the JWT tokens is stored in an AWS Lambda function. Then, there is a Cron job that can be exploited using symlinks to gain arbitrary read. Knowledge about Git, JWT, SSTI and AWS Lambda, as well as Cron job exploitation, is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Nunchucks</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nunchucks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nunchucks/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a webpage vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI) and system capabilities set, but with some protections. Knowledge about Node.js templates and Perl are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Spider</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI) in two fields and SQL injection (SQLi), and an internal website that is vulnerable to XML External Entity (XXE) injection. Advanced knowledge on SSTI and bypassing techniques, SQLi, XXE and port forwarding skills are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a Python script to exploit SSTI and a Bash script to read file using XXE</description></item></channel></rss>