<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>jwt on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/jwt/</link><description>Recent content in jwt on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/jwt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unicode</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses JWT tokens with JWKS and JKU that can be forged to arrive to a directory path traversal vulnerability that can be exploited using some Unicode bypassing. After that, there is a Python compiled binary that can be run with sudo and uses curl behind the hoods. Some JWT knowledge, path traversal and command injection bypassing techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to exploit a directory path traversal using JWT with JWKS</description></item><item><title>Backend</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backend/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backend/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has an API where we can create a new account after some exploration. Then we can find some documentation in Swagger format where we see an endpoint to execute commands and to read files from the server. We must find the secret key used to sign JWT tokens in order to create a valid token to execute commands. Knowledge on JWT tokens and API enumeration are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Secret</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy Machine. This machine contains an API that uses JWT tokens for authentication. We can download the proyect and discover that it is a Git repository, so that we can see the secret key in previous commits and exploit a command injection vulnerability. There is a SUID binary that reads files as root although it only shows some statistics of the file, but we are able to kill the process and read the coredump. Web exploitation techniques, Git enumeration and knowledge about Linux processes are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Epsilon</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that exposes Git repository with secrets in old commits. There is a website that needs a valid JWT token in order to exploit an SSTI vulnerability. The secret for the JWT tokens is stored in an AWS Lambda function. Then, there is a Cron job that can be exploited using symlinks to gain arbitrary read. Knowledge about Git, JWT, SSTI and AWS Lambda, as well as Cron job exploitation, is needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>