<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jwt on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/jwt/</link><description>Recent content in Jwt on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:41:59 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/jwt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RegistryTwo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/registrytwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/registrytwo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine exposes a web application that allows to create custom domains with HTML code. Moreover, there is a Docker registry exposed where we can download Docker image blobs after getting a suitable JWT token. The web application is running a WAR file with Tomcat, we can decompile it and see that it queries a RMI server. Since Tomcat is behind an nginx reverse proxy, we can access some sensitive Tomcat &lt;em>servlets&lt;/em> to modify our session and set manager permissions on the web application. We need this to modify the RMI configuration using a mass assignment vulnerability and point the RMI server to us. After that, we can exploit an insecure deserialization vulnerability in Java to get RCE in a container. Then, we can interact with the legitimate RMI server using port forwarding. This server allows us to read arbitrary files with a directory traversal attack. We can find a plaintext password for user &lt;code>developer&lt;/code>, which is reused in SSH. Then, &lt;code>root&lt;/code> is executing a JAR file to analyze files of the hosting website by sending them to a ClamAV server. The problem here is that the JAR calls functions from the RMI register, which is restarted periodically. Therefore, we can craft a malicious RMI registry and exploit win a race condition to take the port, so that &lt;code>root&lt;/code> queries our malicious registry and talks to our fake ClamAV server. The result is that all files at &lt;code>/root&lt;/code> will be quarantined inside a readable directory, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intentions/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website with an API that is vulnerable to second-order SQLi. Then, there is an authentication mechanism that just requires the password hash, so we can take a hash from the dumped database and log in as an administrator. Then, there is a vulnerability involving PHP and ImageMagick that leads to RCE. Once in the machine, we can pivot to user &lt;code>greg&lt;/code> by analyzing a Git repository and finding plaintext credentials. After that, we are allowed to run a custom binary that hashes a given length of a file and compares the result with a set of pre-computed MD5 hashes. This binary has a capability that allows to read files as &lt;code>root&lt;/code>, which can be used to extract all the contents of any file after automating the process, which allows to read an SSH private key for &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Awkward</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/awkward/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/awkward/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website built in Vue.js that exposes a login form which can be easily bypassed. Then we find an API endpoint that tests connectivity of other websites, which can be exploited using Server-Side Request Forgery to find an internal API documentation. There we have some Node.js code to analyze and see how we can bypass some checks to obtain all the users information and crack a password hash. After that, we can log in, get a valid JWT token and crack it to find the secret. Therefore, we can forge any JWT token, which means we can inject any payload as token information. Using this power, we can read arbitrary files from the server exploiting &lt;code>awk&lt;/code> and find plaintext credentials inside a compressed archive. Next, we can access via SSH and find out another website built with PHP with two vulnerabilities. There is also a Cron task that takes information from a CSV file to send an email. The key here is to inject a malicious parameter in the CSV file so that the &lt;code>mail&lt;/code> command executes a malicious script, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Unicode</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses JWT tokens with JWKS and JKU that can be forged to arrive to a directory path traversal vulnerability that can be exploited using some Unicode bypassing. After that, there is a Python compiled binary that can be run with sudo and uses curl behind the hoods. Some JWT knowledge, path traversal and command injection bypassing techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to exploit a directory path traversal using JWT with JWKS</description></item><item><title>Backend</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backend/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backend/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has an API where we can create a new account after some exploration. Then we can find some documentation in Swagger format where we see an endpoint to execute commands and to read files from the server. We must find the secret key used to sign JWT tokens in order to create a valid token to execute commands. Knowledge on JWT tokens and API enumeration are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Secret</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy Machine. This machine contains an API that uses JWT tokens for authentication. We can download the proyect and discover that it is a Git repository, so that we can see the secret key in previous commits and exploit a command injection vulnerability. There is a SUID binary that reads files as root although it only shows some statistics of the file, but we are able to kill the process and read the coredump. Web exploitation techniques, Git enumeration and knowledge about Linux processes are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Epsilon</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that exposes Git repository with secrets in old commits. There is a website that needs a valid JWT token in order to exploit an SSTI vulnerability. The secret for the JWT tokens is stored in an AWS Lambda function. Then, there is a Cron job that can be exploited using symlinks to gain arbitrary read. Knowledge about Git, JWT, SSTI and AWS Lambda, as well as Cron job exploitation, is needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>