<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>metadata on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/metadata/</link><description>Recent content in metadata on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/metadata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Precious</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/precious/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/precious/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application that uses a tool to create PDF documents which is vulnerable to command injection, which leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE). Then, we can find plaintext credentials to switch to another user. And this user has &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code> permissions to run a Ruby script that is vulnerable to insecure deserialization in YAML, which can be used to execute commands as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Interface</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/interface/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/interface/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a dummy Next.js website that exposes a subdomain in the &lt;code>Content-Security-Policy&lt;/code> header. There, we can enumerate third-party dependencies like &lt;code>dompdf&lt;/code>. This one is vulnerable to Remote Code Execution. After a lot of enumeration to interact with &lt;code>dompdf&lt;/code>, we find a way to get a reverse shell on the system. Then, user &lt;code>root&lt;/code> executes a shell script each minute, and the script is vulnerable to command injection, which must be exploited by adding malicious metadata to a temporary file. By chaining these steps, we are able to get a reverse shell as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Investigation</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/investigation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/investigation/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that allows to analyze image file metadata with &lt;code>exiftool&lt;/code>. However, the version is vulnerable to command injection and can be used to access the system. Then, we find some Windows event logs and a plaintext password as username, probably a mistake. After that, we gain access as another user that is able to execute a binary with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which behind the scenes runs a Perl script that leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>RedPanda</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/redpanda/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/redpanda/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application built with Spring Boot that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection with a particular format. After that, in order to escalate privileges, we must analyze a Java program, enter some malicious metadata in a JPEG image, add an XML External Entity into a controlled XML file, break a log parser logic and finally wait for root to process the XML file and read its private SSH key</description></item><item><title>Faculty</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/faculty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/faculty/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to SQLi and autentication bypass which leads to a website where we can export HTML content to PDF. There is a vulnerability where we can attach local files to the PDF file and read a password reused for SSH. Using sudo we can execute a Node.js script as another user and exploit a command injection vulnerability. This second user is allowed to run GDB and moreover GDB has cap_sys_ptrace capability set, so we can debug a process running as root and run arbitrary code</description></item><item><title>Acute</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/acute/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/acute/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Hard machine. This machine exposes a website where we can find a Word document with useful information and some usernames. There is a PowerShell Web Access where we can access using a default credential and extract another password from a screenshot. There is an Active Directory domain controller where we can execute commands as other users. We will be able to connect to the first machine and dump NTLM hashes and finally become domain administrator. Deep knowledge on PowerShell commands and basic Windows and Active Directory exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Intelligence</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intelligence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intelligence/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Medium machine. This machine presents an Active Directory (AD) environment to perform user enumeration, network poisoning and a Silver Ticket attack. Some scripting, DNS operations, AD attacks and BloodHound basics are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Go script to fuzz for files in a web server</description></item></channel></rss>