<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>api on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/api/</link><description>Recent content in api on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RainyDay</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rainyday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rainyday/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website vulnerable to user enumeration. Then we can use brute force a user&amp;rsquo;s password and run containers. Using a container we can access an internal website that has an API that shows sensitive information using Type Juggling and has a feature for matching regular expressions on given files, so that we can read source code and get the secret key for Flask. Then, we can forge a session for user &lt;code>jack&lt;/code> and find out that the Docker containers allow to access process information from the machine, and we can read the private SSH key of this user. Next, we can run a custom Python interpreter and escape the sandbox to get a shell as &lt;code>jack_adm&lt;/code>. Finally, we have a tool to generate hashes with &lt;code>bcrypt&lt;/code>, and we need to exploit a limitation of &lt;code>bcrypt&lt;/code> to extract a secret pepper string and then crack &lt;code>root&lt;/code>&amp;rsquo;s hash in order to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Catch</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine offers an APK file that contains hard-coded authentication tokens for some services exposed by the machine. One of the tokens can be used to enumerate a Let&amp;rsquo;s Chat application using its API and get credentials for Cachet. This service is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection in PHP and we can get more credentials to access via SSH. The machine has a Cron job configured to analyze APK files using a Bash script that is vulnerable to command injection, so we need to upload a maliciously crafted APK file to exploit it and become root</description></item><item><title>RouterSpace</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/routerspace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/routerspace/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a downloadable APK file with a simple app. This app performs a web request to an API the needs th be captured with a proxy, and this API is vulnerable to a command injection. After that, we can access to the machine via SSH and basic enumeration shows that the version of sudo is vulnerable</description></item><item><title>Backend</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backend/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backend/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has an API where we can create a new account after some exploration. Then we can find some documentation in Swagger format where we see an endpoint to execute commands and to read files from the server. We must find the secret key used to sign JWT tokens in order to create a valid token to execute commands. Knowledge on JWT tokens and API enumeration are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Secret</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy Machine. This machine contains an API that uses JWT tokens for authentication. We can download the proyect and discover that it is a Git repository, so that we can see the secret key in previous commits and exploit a command injection vulnerability. There is a SUID binary that reads files as root although it only shows some statistics of the file, but we are able to kill the process and read the coredump. Web exploitation techniques, Git enumeration and knowledge about Linux processes are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Devzat</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/devzat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/devzat/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains chat service over SSH and a hidden web subdomain vulnerable to command injection. Then we can access the machine and exploit a vulnerable version of InluxDB to extract the password for another user. This user has permissions to see a development project for the SSH chat that allows to read arbitrary files from the server. Basic web exploitation and Linux enumeration techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>SteamCloud</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/steamcloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/steamcloud/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a Kubernetes cluster that exposes the kubelet and it is vulnerable to unauthenticated RCE. We are able to extract credentials from a running Pod and use them to create a malicious Pod that mounts the hosts file system. Basic knowledge about pentesting on Kubernetes is needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>