<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>file-upload on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/file-upload/</link><description>Recent content in file-upload on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/file-upload/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Late</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/late/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/late/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a Flask web application that extracts text from images and renders them, being vulnerable to SSTI. Then there is a PAM configured for SSH with relative paths that can be abused because of some privileges to override executables. Basic web exploitation and Linux enumeration skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Timing</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP web application that is vulnerable to user enumeration, LFI, Type Juggling and SQLi, apart from some other bugs and misconfigurations. After reading the PHP source code, we find a way to upload a PHP web shell and get RCE. After that, we find a password inside a Git repository and access via SSH. Then, we can run a JAR file using sudo that downloads files as root, and we can use a symlink to write an authorized SSH key for root</description></item><item><title>Overflow</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Padding Oracle Attack and Bit Flipper Attack to login as admin and also vulnerable to SQLi by a CMS. There is another subdomain that runs a version of exiftool that has an RCE vulnerability. Once in the machine, lateral movements are relatively easy and privilege escalation consists of reversing and exploiting a Buffer Overflow vulnerability on a SUID binary. Deep knowledge on web exploitation, cryptography and binary exploitation are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform a Bit Flipper Attack and a Ruby script to exploit SQLi</description></item><item><title>Driver</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine contains a website with default credentials authentication and a file upload. Here we can upload an SCF to capture the user&amp;rsquo;s NTLMv2 hash and crack it. Then we can exploit PrintNightmare. Windows basic exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>