<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pgp-Keys on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/pgp-keys/</link><description>Recent content in Pgp-Keys on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:41:59 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/pgp-keys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sandworm</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sandworm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sandworm/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that allows to encrypt, decrypt and verify signatures using PGP. The website is vulnerable to SSTI in Flask, which is the way to access the machine as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code>. However, this environment is limited due to &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code>, but we are able to find a plaintext password to login as &lt;code>silentobserver&lt;/code> in SSH. As this user, we are able to modify a Rust project that is used in another Rust project that runs periodically as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code>. With this power, we can get access as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code> again, but outside &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code>. Finally, since &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code> is a SUID binary, we can use a public exploit to become &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>MetaTwo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/metatwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/metatwo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a WordPress website that uses a plugin that is vulnerable to SQLi. Then we can get password hashes and crack one of them to get access to the WordPress dashboard. The version of WordPress is vulnerable to out-of-band XXE using a WAV file that allows to read files from the server. Using this vulnerability, we can find plaintext credentials for FTP. In this service we have another PHP file with more plaintext credentials that are valid for SSH. Once inside the machine, we can see some PGP keys and messages that can be decrypted to find the password for &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Bolt</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has several virtual hosts and a Docker image that contains a lot of information needed to exploit the websites. There is an SSTI vulnerability between two websites interaction. Then we can extract a PGP private key from Google Chrome cache and decrypt a message. Deep knowledge about Docker and basic web exploitation skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>