<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pgp-keys on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/pgp-keys/</link><description>Recent content in pgp-keys on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/pgp-keys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MetaTwo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/metatwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/metatwo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a WordPress website that uses a plugin that is vulnerable to SQLi. Then we can get password hashes and crack one of them to get access to the WordPress dashboard. The version of WordPress is vulnerable to out-of-band XXE using a WAV file that allows to read files from the server. Using this vulnerability, we can find plaintext credentials for FTP. In this service we have another PHP file with more plaintext credentials that are valid for SSH. Once inside the machine, we can see some PGP keys and messages that can be decrypted to find the password for &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Bolt</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has several virtual hosts and a Docker image that contains a lot of information needed to exploit the websites. There is an SSTI vulnerability between two websites interaction. Then we can extract a PGP private key from Google Chrome cache and decrypt a message. Deep knowledge about Docker and basic web exploitation skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>