<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>port-forwarding on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/port-forwarding/</link><description>Recent content in port-forwarding on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/port-forwarding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Explore</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/explore/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/explore/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Android. Easy machine. This is a mobile device that uses a vulnerable application that exposes files that provide access via SSH. Some port scanning, port forwarding and Android skills are needed to compromise this device</description></item><item><title>Spider</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</guid><description>Linux. Hard machine</description></item><item><title>Monitors</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a Wordpress web site with a plugin vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal, another website vulnerable to SQL injection, and yet another webpage vulnerable to Insecure Deserialization running inside a Docker container with system capabilities enabled. Deep knowledge about web enumeration, vulnerabilities and exploitation techniques, as well as port forwarding and Docker escaping methods are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to exploit Insecure Deserialization</description></item><item><title>Antique</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/antique/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/antique/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine is a HP JetDirect printer that exposes its password through SNMP and has an arbritrary file read vulnerability. SNMP enumeration and port forwarding techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to obtain a clear-text password</description></item></channel></rss>