<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Newsletters on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/</link><description>Recent content in Newsletters on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Newsletter 22/02/2023</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-02-22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-02-22/</guid><description>RainyDay Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine 25 minutes to read This machine has a website vulnerable to user enumeration. Then we can use brute force a user&amp;rsquo;s password and run containers. Using a container we can access an internal website that has an API that shows sensitive information using Type Juggling and has a feature for matching regular expressions on given files, so that we can read source code and get the secret key for Flask.</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 13/02/2023</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-02-13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-02-13/</guid><description>Photobomb Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine 8 minutes to read This machine contains a web application built with Sinatra that is vulnerable to command injection, which leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE). The user has sudo permissions to run a Bash script that is vulnerable to PATH hijacking, which can be used to escalate privileges
Kryptos Support Hack The Box. Challenges. Web 6 minutes to read Cross-Site Scripting. Insecure Direct Object Reference</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 08/02/2023</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-02-08/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-02-08/</guid><description>baby todo or not todo Hack The Box. Challenges. Web 4 minutes to read Broken Access Control
baby website rick Hack The Box. Challenges. Web 3 minutes to read Insecure deserialization with pickle
Optimus Prime Hack The Box. Challenges. Crypto 4 minutes to read RSA. Greatest Common Divisor
Easy DSA: Elated once ImaginaryCTF 24/01/2023 8 minutes to read 100 points. DSA. LCG. Modular system of equations
Easy DSA: Lovely Little Lane ImaginaryCTF 21/01/2023 4 minutes to read 125 points.</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 31/01/2023</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-01-31/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-01-31/</guid><description>Ambassador Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine 11 minutes to read This machine has a Grafana instance that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal without authentication. There, we can read files from the server and find the password for Grafana and for MySQL. After that, we can connect to MySQL, which is exposed, and find another password to access via SSH. The machine runs consul internally with a vulnerable configuration.</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 24/01/2023</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-01-24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-01-24/</guid><description>UpDown Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine 13 minutes to read This machine has a website that has a development directory and exposes a Git repository. Using this, we can find some functionality that is hidden except for developers and can be abused to get RCE after planning the attack and bypassing disable_functions in PHP. In the machine, there&amp;rsquo;s a SUID binary compiled out of a Python script, which can be abused with a library hijacking attack.</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 16/01/2023</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-01-16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-01-16/</guid><description>Shoppy Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine 8 minutes to read This machine website that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection. Using this vulnerability, we can bypass authentication and list some hashed passwords that can be cracked. Then, we enumerate subdomains and find a MatterMost application in which we can access and find credentials for SSH in the machine. The first user is able to run a custom ELF binary that shows more credentials when using a specific master password.</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 08/01/2023</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-01-08/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2023-01-08/</guid><description>Health Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine 18 minutes to read This machine has a webhook functionality that seems vulnerable to Server-Side Request Forgery. After trying some bypasses, we see that the SSRF attack can be performed using a redirection. Internally, there is an outdated Gogs version that is vulnerable to SQLi. Once found a payload to extract password hashes from the database, we can obtain and crack the hashes from the remote Gogs instance with SQLi through SSRF.</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 19/12/2022</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-12-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-12-19/</guid><description>Space Hack The Box. Challenges. Pwn 5 minutes to read 32-bit binary. Buffer Overflow. Custom shellcode
misDIRection Hack The Box. Challenges. Misc 3 minutes to read Guess string. Base64
Fake News Hack The Box. Challenges. Forensics 3 minutes to read PHP and JavaScript deobfuscation. Disc image inspection
Situated ImaginaryCTF 03/11/2022 1 minute to read 50 points. Inspect HTML code
Robotic ImaginaryCTF 04/11/2022 1 minute to read 50 points. robots.txt</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 12/12/2022</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-12-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-12-12/</guid><description>AESWCM HTB UniCTF 2022. Crypto. Medium 7 minutes to read Custom encryption using AES and XOR. Bad padding implementation
Bank-er-smith HTB UniCTF 2022. Crypto. Easy 7 minutes to read RSA known bits. Coppersmith method. LLL lattice reduction
BatchCraft Potions HTB UniCTF 2022. Web. Medium 22 minutes to read GraphQL batching attack. OTP and rate limit bypass. JWT. CSP. DOM Clobbering. XSS
Curse Breaker HTB UniCTF 2022. Reversing. Medium 14 minutes to read seccomp rules.</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 27/11/2022</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-11-27/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-11-27/</guid><description>RedPanda Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine 10 minutes to read This machine contains a web application built with Spring Boot that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection with a particular format. After that, in order to escalate privileges, we must analyze a Java program, enter some malicious metadata in a JPEG image, add an XML External Entity into a controlled XML file, break a log parser logic and finally wait for root to process the XML file and read its private SSH key</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 20/11/2022</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-11-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-11-20/</guid><description>Nightmare Hack The Box. Challenges. Pwn 10 minutes to read 64-bit binary. Format String vulnerability. GOT overwrite
Optimistic Hack The Box. Challenges. Pwn 9 minutes to read 64-bit binary. Buffer Overflow. Integer Overflow. Alphanumeric shellcode
PwnShop Hack The Box. Challenges. Pwn 14 minutes to read 64-bit binary. Buffer Overflow. PIE and ASLR bypass. Special ROP chain. Ret2Libc
Secured Transfer Hack The Box. Challenges. Reversing 7 minutes to read Network traffic analysis with Wireshark.</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 13/11/2022</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-11-13/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-11-13/</guid><description>Shared Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine 11 minutes to read This machine has an e-commerce store that is vulnerable to SQLi. With this vulnerability we can get a hashed password which is reused for SSH. There is another user that runs ipython periodically, so we can inject a configuration file to execute commands. The second user is able to use a binary compiled in Go that connects to Redis.</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 07/11/2022</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-11-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-11-07/</guid><description>CRSid Hack The Box. Challenges. Pwn 24 minutes to read 64-bit binary. Heap exploitation. Safe-linking. Out-of-bounds write. Tcache poisoning. Exit handlers
AHS512 Hack The Box. Challenges. Crypto 5 minutes to read Custom hash function. Bit operations
Fast Carmichael Hack The Box. Challenges. Crypto 2 minutes to read Miller-Rabin primality test
Gonna-Lift-Em-All Hack The Box. Challenges. Crypto 2 minutes to read Modular arithmetic
Horror Feeds Hack The Box. Challenges. Web 4 minutes to read Stack-based SQL injection</description></item><item><title>Newsletter 30/10/2022</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-10-30/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/newsletters/2022-10-30/</guid><description>Trick Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine 17 minutes to read This machine has a DNS service that is vulnerable to a Domain Zone Transfer attack and leaks a subdomain. Here we can bypass authentication with SQLi and exploit an LFI. Both vulnerabilities can be chained to get access to the machine. Then, we find another subdomain that is again vulnerable to LFI, and we can leak a user&amp;rsquo;s SSH private key.</description></item></channel></rss>