<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Format-String on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/format-string/</link><description>Recent content in Format-String on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 17:28:44 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/format-string/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Static</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/static/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/static/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that exposes a corrupted Gzip file that must be patched to get a TOTP key and download a VPN file. Then there are some PHP vulnerable services that can be compromised and get to an internal server that contains a binary executable file having a Format String vulnerability. Deep knowledge about pivoting and port forwarding techniques, network enumeration and PHP exploitation, as well as Format String exploitation are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Ruby script to automate the process of downloading the VPN file, a Python script gain RCE over a PHP web server and another Python script to exploit a binary using Format String</description></item><item><title>Rope</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine exposes a custom web server that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal so we can read files and discover that it is a binary file. After ananlyzing the binary, we discover that it has a Format String vulnerability that can be exploited to get RCE as &lt;code>john&lt;/code>. This user is able to run another binary as user &lt;code>r4j&lt;/code>. This binary uses an external library that we can modify because of its permissions and gain access as &lt;code>r4j&lt;/code>. Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s another binary that runs a local socket server, we can access the binary and analyze it to find out a Buffer Overflow vulnerability. The binary has all protections set, but it is still exploitable to get RCE as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item></channel></rss>