<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rce on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/rce/</link><description>Recent content in rce on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/rce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sau</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sau/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sau/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a web application that is vulnerable to SSRF, which can be used to read the contents of an internal server, which is vulnerable to command injection. The two vulnerabilities can be chained to get RCE on the machine. The low-privileged user is able to run &lt;code>systemctl&lt;/code> as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> using &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which leads to the privilege escalation via the default pager &lt;code>less&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Pilgrimage</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pilgrimage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pilgrimage/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that exposes a Git repository. We are able to extract the PHP source of the web application and find out that it uses ImageMagick under the hood to process uploaded images. The version of ImageMagick has a local file read vulnerability that can be used to read a SQLite database file and find a plaintext password for &lt;code>emily&lt;/code>, which is used in SSH too. After that, we find that &lt;code>root&lt;/code> executes a Bash script that uses &lt;code>binwalk&lt;/code> to remove malware from uploaded image files. The version of &lt;code>binwalk&lt;/code> is vulnerable to Remote Code Execution, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Sandworm</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sandworm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sandworm/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that allows to encrypt, decrypt and verify signatures using PGP. The website is vulnerable to SSTI in Flask, which is the way to access the machine as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code>. However, this environment is limited due to &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code>, but we are able to find a plaintext password to login as &lt;code>silentobserver&lt;/code> in SSH. As this user, we are able to modify a Rust project that is used in another Rust project that runs periodically as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code>. With this power, we can get access as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code> again, but outside &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code>. Finally, since &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code> is a SUID binary, we can use a public exploit to become &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Topology</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/topology/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/topology/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a website that allows to generate equations using LaTeX. With this feature we can read arbitrary files from the server with LaTeX injection techniques and find a hashed password for another subdomain, which can be cracked. This password is reused in SSH. After that, &lt;code>root&lt;/code> is executing &lt;code>gnuplot&lt;/code> scripts periodically, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intentions/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website with an API that is vulnerable to second-order SQLi. Then, there is an authentication mechanism that just requires the password hash, so we can take a hash from the dumped database and log in as an administrator. Then, there is a vulnerability involving PHP and ImageMagick that leads to RCE. Once in the machine, we can pivot to user &lt;code>greg&lt;/code> by analyzing a Git repository and finding plaintext credentials. After that, we are allowed to run a custom binary that hashes a given length of a file and compares the result with a set of pre-computed MD5 hashes. This binary has a capability that allows to read files as &lt;code>root&lt;/code>, which can be used to extract all the contents of any file after automating the process, which allows to read an SSH private key for &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>MonitorsTwo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitorstwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitorstwo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a Cacti service that is vulnerable to unauthenticated Remote Code Execution that grants access to a Docker container. Here we can find credentials in the database and reuse them for SSH on the host machine. Then, we find out that the Docker version is vulnerable to a CVE. To exploit this, we need to get &lt;code>root&lt;/code> in the container and configure a SUID binary that will be executed from the host machine via directory traversal to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Soccer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/soccer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/soccer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a Tiny File Manager application that allows us to upload and execute PHP, so we can obtain a reverse shell as &lt;code>www-data&lt;/code>. In the machine, we can read the configuration for nginx and find another subdomain. This one exposes a WebSocket server that is vulnerable to Boolean-based Blind SQLi. By exploiting SQLi, we can find plaintext credentials that are reused in SSH. Finally, the user is allowed to run &lt;code>dstat&lt;/code> as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> using &lt;code>doas&lt;/code>, and we are able to create a plugin to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Precious</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/precious/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/precious/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application that uses a tool to create PDF documents which is vulnerable to command injection, which leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE). Then, we can find plaintext credentials to switch to another user. And this user has &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code> permissions to run a Ruby script that is vulnerable to insecure deserialization in YAML, which can be used to execute commands as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Interface</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/interface/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/interface/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a dummy Next.js website that exposes a subdomain in the &lt;code>Content-Security-Policy&lt;/code> header. There, we can enumerate third-party dependencies like &lt;code>dompdf&lt;/code>. This one is vulnerable to Remote Code Execution. After a lot of enumeration to interact with &lt;code>dompdf&lt;/code>, we find a way to get a reverse shell on the system. Then, user &lt;code>root&lt;/code> executes a shell script each minute, and the script is vulnerable to command injection, which must be exploited by adding malicious metadata to a temporary file. By chaining these steps, we are able to get a reverse shell as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Investigation</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/investigation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/investigation/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that allows to analyze image file metadata with &lt;code>exiftool&lt;/code>. However, the version is vulnerable to command injection and can be used to access the system. Then, we find some Windows event logs and a plaintext password as username, probably a mistake. After that, we gain access as another user that is able to execute a binary with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which behind the scenes runs a Perl script that leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>BroScience</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/broscience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/broscience/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website with a Local File Read vulnerability that can be used to read PHP source code and find a way to activate a new account. Then, we can perform a deserialization attack in PHP to get RCE. After that, we find a hashed password in the database that can be cracked and it is reused in the system. Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s a Cron task running by &lt;code>root&lt;/code> to renew OpenSSL certificates and the script has a command injection vulnerability, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Vessel</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/vessel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/vessel/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website that exposes a Git repository. Here we can read the source code of the web application and find out a way to bypass authentication in MySQL with Type Juggling. Then, we find another subdomain that has a public exploit to get RCE. After that, we discover a password generator tool that can be reverse-engineered to generate multiple passwords and crack a password-protected PDF document. Then, we get access via SSH and see that we can use &lt;code>sysctl&lt;/code> as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> with &lt;code>pinns&lt;/code> as SUID binary. With this, we can modify the kernel configuration to run an arbitrary script with a program crashes, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Awkward</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/awkward/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/awkward/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website built in Vue.js that exposes a login form which can be easily bypassed. Then we find an API endpoint that tests connectivity of other websites, which can be exploited using Server-Side Request Forgery to find an internal API documentation. There we have some Node.js code to analyze and see how we can bypass some checks to obtain all the users information and crack a password hash. After that, we can log in, get a valid JWT token and crack it to find the secret. Therefore, we can forge any JWT token, which means we can inject any payload as token information. Using this power, we can read arbitrary files from the server exploiting &lt;code>awk&lt;/code> and find plaintext credentials inside a compressed archive. Next, we can access via SSH and find out another website built with PHP with two vulnerabilities. There is also a Cron task that takes information from a CSV file to send an email. The key here is to inject a malicious parameter in the CSV file so that the &lt;code>mail&lt;/code> command executes a malicious script, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Photobomb</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/photobomb/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/photobomb/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application built with Sinatra that is vulnerable to command injection, which leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE). The user has &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code> permissions to run a Bash script that is vulnerable to &lt;code>PATH&lt;/code> hijacking, which can be used to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Ambassador</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ambassador/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ambassador/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a Grafana instance that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal without authentication. There, we can read files from the server and find the password for Grafana and for MySQL. After that, we can connect to MySQL, which is exposed, and find another password to access via SSH. The machine runs &lt;code>consul&lt;/code> internally with a vulnerable configuration. After finding an authentication token in a Git repository, we can use an exploit to get RCE from &lt;code>consul&lt;/code> and get access as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>UpDown</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/updown/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/updown/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that has a development directory and exposes a Git repository. Using this, we can find some functionality that is hidden except for developers and can be abused to get RCE after planning the attack and bypassing &lt;code>disable_functions&lt;/code> in PHP. In the machine, there&amp;rsquo;s a SUID binary compiled out of a Python script, which can be abused with a library hijacking attack. Finally, the developer user is able to run &lt;code>easy_install&lt;/code> with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>RedPanda</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/redpanda/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/redpanda/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application built with Spring Boot that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection with a particular format. After that, in order to escalate privileges, we must analyze a Java program, enter some malicious metadata in a JPEG image, add an XML External Entity into a controlled XML file, break a log parser logic and finally wait for root to process the XML file and read its private SSH key</description></item><item><title>Shared</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shared/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shared/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has an e-commerce store that is vulnerable to SQLi. With this vulnerability we can get a hashed password which is reused for SSH. There is another user that runs ipython periodically, so we can inject a configuration file to execute commands. The second user is able to use a binary compiled in Go that connects to Redis. A binary analysis reveals the password, so we can connect to Redis and exploit a CVE to run Lua code, escape from the sandbox and execute system commands as root</description></item><item><title>Trick</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/trick/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/trick/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a DNS service that is vulnerable to a Domain Zone Transfer attack and leaks a subdomain. Here we can bypass authentication with SQLi and exploit an LFI. Both vulnerabilities can be chained to get access to the machine. Then, we find another subdomain that is again vulnerable to LFI, and we can leak a user&amp;rsquo;s SSH private key. This user is able to restart fail2ban with sudo and modify configuration files</description></item><item><title>OpenSource</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/opensource/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/opensource/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website exposes its source code, being vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal. Using this vulnerability we can read the necessary files to compute the PIN for the Flask debug console and get Remote Code Execution in a Docker container. After that, we need to use port forwarding to view a Gitea instance and enter credentials found in a Git repository. Here we have the private SSH key so we can enter as a system user. There is a Cron job that commits new changes of a Git repository and leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Noter</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/noter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/noter/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a web application built with Flask to manage notes in Markdown and PDF. We are able to extract the secret key used to sign session cookies and then forge cookies to enumerate users. Once we have a privileged user, we can access the FTP server and analyze the source code of the web application to detect a command injection vulnerability. Then, we can access the machine and find out that MySQL runs as root, which leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Talkative</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/talkative/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/talkative/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website that exposes a Jamovi application where we can get a reverse shell on a Docker container. Here we find some credentials for a Bolt CMS application, so we get administration access. From here we can modify a template by writing PHP code and get access to another container. This one has connectivity with port 22 of the machine, so we can get access to the machine via SSH reusing credentials. Then, we find that there&amp;rsquo;s another Docker container running MongoDB, which contains the database for a Rocket.Chat server. At this point, we can create a new account on Rocket.Chat and assign us administration role modifying the database entry. After that, we can set a new integration to gain RCE on the container that manages Rocket.Chat. Finally, this container has capability &lt;code>CAP_DAC_READ_SEARCH&lt;/code> enabled, which allows us to read files as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> from the host machine using an exploit. Moreover, the container is also vulnerable to another exploit to write arbitrary files as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> on the host machine</description></item><item><title>Retired</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/retired/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/retired/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP website that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal. There we find a PHP file that expects a file to be uploaded in order to be passed to a local socket server. We are able to enumerate open processes and download the binary that runs the server and see that it is vulnerable to Buffer Overflow. Once exploited, we can pivot to another user using symbolic links. And then, we are allowed to add custom executable formats, which can be exploited to become root. Solid binary exploitation techniques and Linux concepts are required in order to compromise this machine. This write-up contains some custom Python exploits for the foothold part</description></item><item><title>OverGraph</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overgraph/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overgraph/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Open Redirect, a web application built with AngularJS which is vulnerable to Client-Side Template Injection and XSS, and a GraphQL endpoint. We are able to register a new account bypassing an OTP code using a NoSQLi payload. Then, we can perform a CSRF attack abusing the Open Redirect to inject an XSS payload on the victim&amp;rsquo;s profile in order to get an adminToken stored in localStorage. After that, we are able to upload video files that are processed with ffmpeg, so we can exploit a Server-Side Request Forgery vulnerability to read files from the server. Eventually, we will access as a user to the machine and find a binary that is running as root. Having analyzed the binary, we can obtain a valid token to use the program and exploit a vulnerability to write arbitrary data at an arbitrary address, leading to RCE or write permissions as root</description></item><item><title>Late</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/late/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/late/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a Flask web application that extracts text from images and renders them, being vulnerable to SSTI. Then there is a PAM configured for SSH with relative paths that can be abused because of some privileges to ovewrite executables. Basic web exploitation and Linux enumeration skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Undetected</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/undetected/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/undetected/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website in PHP with a third-party dependency that is vulnerable to RCE. The machine has already been compromised and has some backdoors and exploits that need to be detected and analyzed using reverse engineering techniques</description></item><item><title>Meta</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/meta/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that analyzes uploaded images with a vulnerable version of exiftool that leads to RCE. Then, there is a Cron job that transforms images using ImageMagick&amp;rsquo;s mogrify command, which is vulnerable to command injection. Finally, we have sudo permissions on neofetch, which leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Timing</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP web application that is vulnerable to user enumeration, LFI, Type Juggling and SQLi, apart from some other bugs and misconfigurations. After reading the PHP source code, we find a way to upload a PHP web shell and get RCE. After that, we find a password inside a Git repository and access via SSH. Then, we can run a JAR file using sudo that downloads files as root, and we can use a symlink to write an authorized SSH key for root</description></item><item><title>Backdoor</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backdoor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backdoor/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a WordPress website that has a plugin vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal, which can be used to enumerate running processes, and then a SUID binary. WordPress enumeration and experience with file inclusion vulnerabilities is needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to read files from the server and a personal public exploit to gain access to the machine</description></item><item><title>Overflow</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Padding Oracle Attack and Bit Flipper Attack to login as admin and also vulnerable to SQLi by a CMS. There is another subdomain that runs a version of exiftool that has an RCE vulnerability. Once in the machine, lateral movements are relatively easy and privilege escalation consists of reversing and exploiting a Buffer Overflow vulnerability on a SUID binary. Deep knowledge on web exploitation, cryptography and binary exploitation are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform a Bit Flipper Attack and a Ruby script to exploit SQLi</description></item><item><title>Shibboleth</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shibboleth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shibboleth/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a vulnerable IPMI service where we can find a password that is reused for a Zabbix control panel. Here we can enter and get access to the machine. Next, we find a vulnerable version for MariaDB which leads to RCE as root. Good enumeration and pentesting methodology are needed in order to comprimise this machine</description></item><item><title>Altered</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/altered/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/altered/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a PHP website vulnerable to user enumeration. Then we can use brute force on a PIN to reset a password after bypassing rate limits and exploit SQLi and Type Juggling. After that, we see that the Linux kernel is vulnerable to DirtyPipe. Advanced web exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Ruby script to find the valid PIN</description></item><item><title>Secret</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy Machine. This machine contains an API that uses JWT tokens for authentication. We can download the proyect and discover that it is a Git repository, so that we can see the secret key in previous commits and exploit a command injection vulnerability. There is a SUID binary that reads files as root although it only shows some statistics of the file, but we are able to kill the process and read the coredump. Web exploitation techniques, Git enumeration and knowledge about Linux processes are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Stacked</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/stacked/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/stacked/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine contains a LocalStack environment that is vulnerable to CSRF and command injection. By discovering an XSS vulnerability in a subdomain, we can use CSRF to exploit the command injection vulnerability and get RCE inside a container. After escalating privileges inside the container by restarting a service and entering a malicious command, we can interact with Docker from the host machine and create a malicious container from scratch that mounts the host file system into the container to get arbitrary file read and write. Web exploitation techniques and deep Docker knowledge is needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Devzat</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/devzat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/devzat/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains chat service over SSH and a hidden web subdomain vulnerable to command injection. Then we can access the machine and exploit a vulnerable version of InluxDB to extract the password for another user. This user has permissions to see a development project for the SSH chat that allows to read arbitrary files from the server. Basic web exploitation and Linux enumeration techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Hancliffe</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/hancliffe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/hancliffe/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Hard machine. This machine contains a webpage that hides a Nuxeo Java application vulnerable to SSTI by breaking nginx parser logic. Then we find access the machine and find an application that has a public exploit to access as another user. After that, we extract Firefox credentials and use a password generator to login as another user and find a custom Windows PE. Having reversed the binary to obtain the expected credentials, we find a Buffer Overflow vulnerability that must be exploited via Socket Reuse to access as Administrator</description></item><item><title>Driver</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine contains a website with default credentials authentication and a file upload. Here we can upload an SCF to capture the user&amp;rsquo;s NTLMv2 hash and crack it. Then we can exploit PrintNightmare. Windows basic exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>GoodGames</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to SQL injection where we can extract a password to access an internal website that is vulnerable to SSTI. Then, we get access to a Docker container that mounts a directory from the machine, so that we can abuse it to escalate privileges. Basic web exploitation skills and Docker breakout techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>Bolt</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has several virtual hosts and a Docker image that contains a lot of information needed to exploit the websites. There is an SSTI vulnerability between two websites interaction. Then we can extract a PGP private key from Google Chrome cache and decrypt a message. Deep knowledge about Docker and basic web exploitation skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>SteamCloud</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/steamcloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/steamcloud/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a Kubernetes cluster that exposes the kubelet and it is vulnerable to unauthenticated RCE. We are able to extract credentials from a running Pod and use them to create a malicious Pod that mounts the hosts file system. Basic knowledge about pentesting on Kubernetes is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Epsilon</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that exposes Git repository with secrets in old commits. There is a website that needs a valid JWT token in order to exploit an SSTI vulnerability. The secret for the JWT tokens is stored in an AWS Lambda function. Then, there is a Cron job that can be exploited using symlinks to gain arbitrary read. Knowledge about Git, JWT, SSTI and AWS Lambda, as well as Cron job exploitation, is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Horizontall</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/horizontall/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/horizontall/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that hides a valid subdomain that contains a Strapi webapp vulnerable to RCE. There is also an internal Laravel webapp vulnerable to RCE. Some knowledge about JavaScript, PHP and Python, as well as port forwarding techniques, are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom script that chains two exploits for Strapi needed to obtain RCE</description></item><item><title>NodeBlog</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a blog that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection, then to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and finally to insecure deserialization to get Remote Code Execution. Advanced web pentesting techniques and scripting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses custom scripts in Bash, Python and Node.js to exploit all vulnerabilities</description></item><item><title>Previse</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a webpage vulnerable to command injection after bypassing redirects and managing to register a new account. After that, a hash must be cracked to login as a low privileged user and perform a PATH hijacking using sudo. Common web pentesting and Burp Suite skills, as well as common privilege escalation techniques are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a custom Go program to automate the foothold process</description></item><item><title>Writer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to SQL injection. This allows to read the source code of the server and find a vulnerability. Then some command injection techniques to escalate privileges. Some scripting for automating a SQLi exploit, SMB, SMTP and Cron tasks are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses custom Python scripts for SQLi and for the foothold</description></item><item><title>Pikaboo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine uses nginx and Apache web servers with a misconfiguration that derives in directory path traversal and afterwards in local file inclusion. There are credentials for FTP in LDAP and a Cron job that is vulnerable to command injection. Web enumeration, knowledge about nginx and LDAP, file inclusion techniques and command injection tricks are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>LogForge</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses Log4j in a Tomcat server that is vulnerable to JNDI lookup. Then there is an FTP server made in Java that also uses Log4j, but this time it is only vulnerable to information disclosure. Knowlegde about Log4j exploitation, Tomcat, FTP and Wireshark are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Union</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains Union-based SQL injection (SQLi) and command injection vulnerabilities. Some SQLi bypassing techniques and source code analysis skills are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Java program to automate a SQLi attack</description></item><item><title>Seal</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a Tomcat website on top of nginx, which has a configuration vulnerability that leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE), then it has some misconfigurations related to file permissions and sudo commands. Knowledge about Tomcat exploitation and Linux file system is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Nunchucks</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nunchucks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nunchucks/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a webpage vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI) and system capabilities set, but with some protections. Knowledge about Node.js templates and Perl are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Spider</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI) in two fields and SQL injection (SQLi), and an internal website that is vulnerable to XML External Entity (XXE) injection. Advanced knowledge on SSTI and bypassing techniques, SQLi, XXE and port forwarding skills are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a Python script to exploit SSTI and a Bash script to read file using XXE</description></item><item><title>dynstr</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/dynstr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/dynstr/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses a dynamic DNS service vulnerable to command injection and then the machine has sudo permissions for a command that uses a wildard. DNS knowledge, command injection techniques and wildcard abusing skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Monitors</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a WordPress web site with a plugin vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal, another website vulnerable to SQL injection, and yet another webpage vulnerable to Insecure Deserialization running inside a Docker container with system capabilities enabled. Deep knowledge about web enumeration, vulnerabilities and exploitation techniques, as well as port forwarding and Docker escaping methods are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to exploit Insecure Deserialization</description></item><item><title>Antique</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/antique/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/antique/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine is a HP JetDirect printer that exposes its password through SNMP and has an arbritrary file read vulnerability. SNMP enumeration and port forwarding techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to obtain a clear-text password</description></item><item><title>Knife</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/knife/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/knife/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a webpage built on PHP with a version that has a backdoor and sudo permissions configured. Knowledge of the PHP version and basic privilege escalation skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Rope</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine exposes a custom web server that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal so we can read files and discover that it is a binary file. After ananlyzing the binary, we discover that it has a Format String vulnerability that can be exploited to get RCE as john. This user is able to run another binary as user r4j. This binary uses an external library that we can modify because of its permissions and gain access as r4j. Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s another binary that runs a local socket server, we can access the binary and analyze it to find out a Buffer Overflow vulnerability. The binary has all protections set, but it is still exploitable to get RCE as root</description></item><item><title>Netmon</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/netmon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/netmon/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine presents an instance of PRTG Network Monitor which is vulnerable to RCE as system. We can connect to FTP with anonymous credentials and read the backup for a configuration file for PRTG Network Monitor and get an old password, which provides a format to guess the current password. Then we can run the public exploit to get RCE and become Administrator</description></item><item><title>Frolic</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/frolic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/frolic/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that stores some files with different encodings and esoteric languages. In the end, we reach to a PlaySMS instance that is vulnerable to RCE using PHP. The machine has a SUID binary that is vulnerable to Buffer Overflow and leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Jerry</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/jerry/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/jerry/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine exposes a default page with Tomcat. We can access to the manager using default credentials and get Remote Code Execution on the machine as Administrator</description></item><item><title>Blue</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/blue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/blue/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine exposes SMB version 1, which is vulnerable to EternalBlue. Once the exploit is done, we get access as Administrator</description></item><item><title>Lame</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/lame/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/lame/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine exposes vulnerable versions for FTP and SMB services. The SMB service is exploitable and derives in RCE as root</description></item></channel></rss>