<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rce on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/rce/</link><description>Recent content in rce on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/rce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Driver</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine contains a website with default credentials authentication and a file upload. Here we can upload an SCF to capture the user&amp;rsquo;s NTLMv2 hash and crack it. Then we can exploit PrintNightmare. Windows basic exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>GoodGames</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to SQL injection where we can extract a password to access an internal website that is vulnerable to SSTI. Then, we get access to a Docker container that mounts a directory from the machine, so that we can abuse it to escalate privileges. Basic web exploitation skills and Docker breakout techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>Bolt</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has several virtual hosts and a Docker image that contains a lot of information needed to exploit the websites. There is an SSTI vulnerability between two websites interaction. Then we can extract a PGP private key from Google Chrome cache and decrypt a message. Deep knowledge about Docker and basic web exploitation skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>SteamCloud</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/steamcloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/steamcloud/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a Kubernetes cluster that exposes the kubelet and it is vulnerable to unauthenticated RCE. We are able to extract credentials from a running Pod and use them to create a malicious Pod that mounts the hosts file system. Basic knowledge about pentesting on Kubernetes is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Epsilon</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that exposes Git repository with secrets in old commits. There is a website that needs a valid JWT token in order to exploit an SSTI vulnerability. The secret for the JWT tokens is stored in an AWS Lambda function. Then, there is a Cron job that can be exploited using symlinks to gain arbitrary read. Knowledge about Git, JWT, SSTI and AWS Lambda, as well as Cron job exploitation, is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Horizontall</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/horizontall/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/horizontall/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that hides a valid subdomain that contains a Strapi webapp vulnerable to RCE. There is also an internal Laravel webapp vulnerable to RCE. Some knowledge about JavaScript, PHP and Python, as well as port forwarding techniques, are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom script that chains two exploits for Strapi needed to obtain RCE</description></item><item><title>NodeBlog</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a blog that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection, then to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and finally to insecure deserialization to get Remote Code Execution. Advanced web pentesting techniques and scripting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses custom scripts in Bash, Python and Node.js to exploit all vulnerabilities</description></item><item><title>Previse</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a webpage vulnerable to command injection after bypassing redirects and managing to register a new account. After that, a hash must be cracked to login as a low privileged user and perform a PATH hijacking using sudo. Common web pentesting and Burp Suite skills, as well as common privilege escalation techniques are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a custom Go program to automate the foothold process</description></item><item><title>Writer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to SQL injection. This allows to read the source code of the server and find a vulnerability. Then some command injection techniques to escalate privileges. Some scripting for automating a SQLi exploit, SMB, SMTP and Cron tasks are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses custom Python scripts for SQLi and for the foothold</description></item><item><title>Pikaboo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine uses nginx and Apache web servers with a misconfiguration that derives in directory path traversal and afterwards in local file inclusion. There are credentials for FTP in LDAP and a Cron job that is vulnerable to command injection. Web enumeration, knowledge about nginx and LDAP, file inclusion techniques and command injection tricks are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>LogForge</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses Log4j in a Tomcat server that is vulnerable to JNDI lookup. Then there is an FTP server made in Java that also uses Log4j, but this time it is only vulnerable to information disclosure. Knowlegde about Log4j exploitation, Tomcat, FTP and Wireshark are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Union</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains Union-based SQL injection (SQLi) and command injection vulnerabilities. Some SQLi bypassing techniques and source code analysis skills are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Java program to automate a SQLi attack</description></item><item><title>Seal</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a Tomcat website on top of nginx, which has a configuration vulnerability that leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE), then it has some misconfigurations related to file permissions and sudo commands. Knowledge about Tomcat exploitation and Linux file system is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Nunchucks</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nunchucks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nunchucks/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a webpage vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI) and system capabilities set, but with some protections. Knowledge about Node.js templates and Perl are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Spider</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI) in two fields and SQL injection (SQLi), and an internal website that is vulnerable to XML External Entity (XXE) injection. Advanced knowledge on SSTI and bypassing techniques, SQLi, XXE and port forwarding skills are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a Python script to exploit SSTI and a Bash script to read file using XXE</description></item><item><title>dynstr</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/dynstr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/dynstr/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses a dynamic DNS service vulnerable to command injection and then the machine has sudo permissions for a command that uses a wildard. DNS knowledge, command injection techniques and wildcard abusing skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Monitors</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a Wordpress web site with a plugin vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal, another website vulnerable to SQL injection, and yet another webpage vulnerable to Insecure Deserialization running inside a Docker container with system capabilities enabled. Deep knowledge about web enumeration, vulnerabilities and exploitation techniques, as well as port forwarding and Docker escaping methods are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to exploit Insecure Deserialization</description></item><item><title>Antique</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/antique/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/antique/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine is a HP JetDirect printer that exposes its password through SNMP and has an arbritrary file read vulnerability. SNMP enumeration and port forwarding techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to obtain a clear-text password</description></item><item><title>Knife</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/knife/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/knife/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a webpage built on PHP with a version that has a backdoor and sudo permissions configured. Knowledge of the PHP version and basic privilege escalation skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>