<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sqli on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/sqli/</link><description>Recent content in sqli on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/sqli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MetaTwo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/metatwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/metatwo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a WordPress website that uses a plugin that is vulnerable to SQLi. Then we can get password hashes and crack one of them to get access to the WordPress dashboard. The version of WordPress is vulnerable to out-of-band XXE using a WAV file that allows to read files from the server. Using this vulnerability, we can find plaintext credentials for FTP. In this service we have another PHP file with more plaintext credentials that are valid for SSH. Once inside the machine, we can see some PGP keys and messages that can be decrypted to find the password for &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Health</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/health/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/health/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a webhook functionality that seems vulnerable to Server-Side Request Forgery. After trying some bypasses, we see that the SSRF attack can be performed using a redirection. Internally, there is an outdated Gogs version that is vulnerable to SQLi. Once found a payload to extract password hashes from the database, we can obtain and crack the hashes from the remote Gogs instance with SQLi through SSRF. Then, we can connect with SSH and find out that we can enter local paths in the database to read files from the server as root. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform the SSRF attack and another Go program to crack Gogs hashes</description></item><item><title>Shared</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shared/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shared/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has an e-commerce store that is vulnerable to SQLi. With this vulnerability we can get a hashed password which is reused for SSH. There is another user that runs ipython periodically, so we can inject a configuration file to execute commands. The second user is able to use a binary compiled in Go that connects to Redis. A binary analysis reveals the password, so we can connect to Redis and exploit a CVE to run Lua code, escape from the sandbox and execute system commands as root</description></item><item><title>Trick</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/trick/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/trick/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a DNS service that is vulnerable to a Domain Zone Transfer attack and leaks a subdomain. Here we can bypass authentication with SQLi and exploit an LFI. Both vulnerabilities can be chained to get access to the machine. Then, we find another subdomain that is again vulnerable to LFI, and we can leak a user&amp;rsquo;s SSH private key. This user is able to restart fail2ban with sudo and modify configuration files</description></item><item><title>Faculty</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/faculty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/faculty/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to SQLi and autentication bypass which leads to a website where we can export HTML content to PDF. There is a vulnerability where we can attach local files to the PDF file and read a password reused for SSH. Using sudo we can execute a Node.js script as another user and exploit a command injection vulnerability. This second user is allowed to run GDB and moreover GDB has cap_sys_ptrace capability set, so we can debug a process running as root and run arbitrary code</description></item><item><title>Timing</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP web application that is vulnerable to user enumeration, LFI, Type Juggling and SQLi, apart from some other bugs and misconfigurations. After reading the PHP source code, we find a way to upload a PHP web shell and get RCE. After that, we find a password inside a Git repository and access via SSH. Then, we can run a JAR file using sudo that downloads files as root, and we can use a symlink to write an authorized SSH key for root</description></item><item><title>Pandora</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pandora/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pandora/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine exposes sensitive information through SNMP that allows to access the machine. Then we find a local instance of Pandora FMS that has multiple vulnerabilities and they can be exploited to gain RCE as another user. This user is allowed to run a SUID binary that is vulnerable to PATH hijacking, but the attack needs to be performed with an SSH shell. Basic enumeration and pentesting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Overflow</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Padding Oracle Attack and Bit Flipper Attack to login as admin and also vulnerable to SQLi by a CMS. There is another subdomain that runs a version of exiftool that has an RCE vulnerability. Once in the machine, lateral movements are relatively easy and privilege escalation consists of reversing and exploiting a Buffer Overflow vulnerability on a SUID binary. Deep knowledge on web exploitation, cryptography and binary exploitation are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform a Bit Flipper Attack and a Ruby script to exploit SQLi</description></item><item><title>Altered</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/altered/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/altered/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a PHP website vulnerable to user enumeration. Then we can use brute force on a PIN to reset a password after bypassing rate limits and exploit SQLi and Type Juggling. After that, we see that the Linux kernel is vulnerable to DirtyPipe. Advanced web exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Ruby script to find the valid PIN</description></item><item><title>GoodGames</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to SQL injection where we can extract a password to access an internal website that is vulnerable to SSTI. Then, we get access to a Docker container that mounts a directory from the machine, so that we can abuse it to escalate privileges. Basic web exploitation skills and Docker breakout techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>Writer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to SQL injection. This allows to read the source code of the server and find a vulnerability. Then some command injection techniques to escalate privileges. Some scripting for automating a SQLi exploit, SMB, SMTP and Cron tasks are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses custom Python scripts for SQLi and for the foothold</description></item><item><title>Union</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains Union-based SQL injection (SQLi) and command injection vulnerabilities. Some SQLi bypassing techniques and source code analysis skills are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Java program to automate a SQLi attack</description></item><item><title>Spider</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI) in two fields and SQL injection (SQLi), and an internal website that is vulnerable to XML External Entity (XXE) injection. Advanced knowledge on SSTI and bypassing techniques, SQLi, XXE and port forwarding skills are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a Python script to exploit SSTI and a Bash script to read file using XXE</description></item></channel></rss>