<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>directory-path-traversal on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/directory-path-traversal/</link><description>Recent content in directory-path-traversal on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/directory-path-traversal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pikaboo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine uses nginx and Apache web servers with a misconfiguration that derives in directory path traversal and afterwards in local file inclusion. There are credentials for FTP in LDAP and a Cron job that is vulnerable to command injection. Web enumeration, knowledge about nginx and LDAP, file inclusion techniques and command injection tricks are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>LogForge</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses Log4j in a Tomcat server that is vulnerable to JNDI lookup. Then there is an FTP server made in Java that also uses Log4j, but this time it is only vulnerable to information disclosure. Knowlegde about Log4j exploitation, Tomcat, FTP and Wireshark are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Seal</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a Tomcat website on top of nginx, which has a configuration vulnerability that leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE), then it has some misconfigurations related to file permissions and sudo commands. Knowledge about Tomcat exploitation and Linux file system is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Monitors</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a Wordpress web site with a plugin vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal, another website vulnerable to SQL injection, and yet another webpage vulnerable to Insecure Deserialization running inside a Docker container with system capabilities enabled. Deep knowledge about web enumeration, vulnerabilities and exploitation techniques, as well as port forwarding and Docker escaping methods are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to exploit Insecure Deserialization</description></item></channel></rss>