<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Laravel on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/laravel/</link><description>Recent content in Laravel on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 12:33:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/laravel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intentions/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website with an API that is vulnerable to second-order SQLi. Then, there is an authentication mechanism that just requires the password hash, so we can take a hash from the dumped database and log in as an administrator. Then, there is a vulnerability involving PHP and ImageMagick that leads to RCE. Once in the machine, we can pivot to user &lt;code>greg&lt;/code> by analyzing a Git repository and finding plaintext credentials. After that, we are allowed to run a custom binary that hashes a given length of a file and compares the result with a set of pre-computed MD5 hashes. This binary has a capability that allows to read files as &lt;code>root&lt;/code>, which can be used to extract all the contents of any file after automating the process, which allows to read an SSH private key for &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Altered</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/altered/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/altered/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a PHP website vulnerable to user enumeration. Then we can use brute force on a PIN to reset a password after bypassing rate limits and exploit SQLi and Type Juggling. After that, we see that the Linux kernel is vulnerable to DirtyPipe. Advanced web exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Ruby script to find the valid PIN</description></item><item><title>Ransom</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ransom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ransom/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a Laravel website with a login form that is vulnerable to Type Juggling. After that we find a encrypted ZIP file and we can perform a known plaintext attack to extract the files. The password expected for the login form is reused for the root user. Basic knowledge about web pentesting on PHP and knowledge about ZIP files is required in order to comprimise this machine</description></item><item><title>Horizontall</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/horizontall/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/horizontall/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that hides a valid subdomain that contains a Strapi webapp vulnerable to RCE. There is also an internal Laravel webapp vulnerable to RCE. Some knowledge about JavaScript, PHP and Python, as well as port forwarding techniques, are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom script that chains two exploits for Strapi needed to obtain RCE</description></item></channel></rss>