<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mongodb on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/mongodb/</link><description>Recent content in mongodb on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/mongodb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shoppy</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection. Using this vulnerability, we can bypass authentication and list some hashed passwords that can be cracked. Then, we enumerate subdomains and find a MatterMost application in which we can access and find credentials for SSH in the machine. The first user is able to run a custom ELF binary that shows more credentials when using a specific master password. Finally, we can escalate privileges because the second user belongs to group docker</description></item><item><title>Talkative</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/talkative/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/talkative/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website that exposes a Jamovi application where we can get a reverse shell on a Docker container. Here we find some credentials for a Bolt CMS application, so we get administration access. From here we can modify a template by writing PHP code and get access to another container. This one has connectivity with port 22 of the machine, so we can get access to the machine via SSH reusing credentials. Then, we find that there&amp;rsquo;s another Docker container running MongoDB, which contains the database for a Rocket.Chat server. At this point, we can create a new account on Rocket.Chat and assign us administration role modifying the database entry. After that, we can set a new integration to gain RCE on the container that manages Rocket.Chat. Finally, this container has capability &lt;code>CAP_DAC_READ_SEARCH&lt;/code> enabled, which allows us to read files as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> from the host machine using an exploit. Moreover, the container is also vulnerable to another exploit to write arbitrary files as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> on the host machine.</description></item><item><title>NodeBlog</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a blog that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection, then to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and finally to insecure deserialization to get Remote Code Execution. Advanced web pentesting techniques and scripting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses custom scripts in Bash, Python and Node.js to exploit all vulnerabilities</description></item></channel></rss>