<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nginx on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/nginx/</link><description>Recent content in nginx on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/nginx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unicode</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses JWT tokens with JWKS and JKU that can be forged to arrive to a directory path traversal vulnerability that can be exploited using some Unicode bypassing. After that, there is a Python compiled binary that can be run with sudo and uses curl behind the hoods. Some JWT knowledge, path traversal and command injection bypassing techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to exploit a directory path traversal using JWT with JWKS</description></item><item><title>Hancliffe</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/hancliffe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/hancliffe/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Hard machine. This machine contains a webpage that hides a Nuxeo Java application vulnerable to SSTI by breaking nginx parser logic. Then we find access the machine and find an application that has a public exploit to access as another user. After that, we extract Firefox credentials and use a password generator to login as another user and find a custom Windows PE. Having reversed the binary to obtain the expected credentials, we find a Buffer Overflow vulnerability that must be exploited via Socket Reuse to access as Administrator</description></item><item><title>SteamCloud</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/steamcloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/steamcloud/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a Kubernetes cluster that exposes the kubelet and it is vulnerable to unauthenticated RCE. We are able to extract credentials from a running Pod and use them to create a malicious Pod that mounts the hosts file system. Basic knowledge about pentesting on Kubernetes is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Seal</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a Tomcat website on top of nginx, which has a configuration vulnerability that leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE), then it has some misconfigurations related to file permissions and sudo commands. Knowledge about Tomcat exploitation and Linux file system is needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>