<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>path-hijacking on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/path-hijacking/</link><description>Recent content in path-hijacking on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/path-hijacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Photobomb</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/photobomb/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/photobomb/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application built with Sinatra that is vulnerable to command injection, which leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE). The user has &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code> permissions to run a Bash script that is vulnerable to &lt;code>PATH&lt;/code> hijacking, which can be used to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Late</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/late/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/late/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a Flask web application that extracts text from images and renders them, being vulnerable to SSTI. Then there is a PAM configured for SSH with relative paths that can be abused because of some privileges to ovewrite executables. Basic web exploitation and Linux enumeration skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Pandora</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pandora/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pandora/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine exposes sensitive information through SNMP that allows to access the machine. Then we find a local instance of Pandora FMS that has multiple vulnerabilities and they can be exploited to gain RCE as another user. This user is allowed to run a SUID binary that is vulnerable to PATH hijacking, but the attack needs to be performed with an SSH shell. Basic enumeration and pentesting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Previse</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a webpage vulnerable to command injection after bypassing redirects and managing to register a new account. After that, a hash must be cracked to login as a low privileged user and perform a PATH hijacking using sudo. Common web pentesting and Burp Suite skills, as well as common privilege escalation techniques are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a custom Go program to automate the foothold process</description></item><item><title>Static</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/static/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/static/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that exposes a corrupted Gzip file that must be patched to get a TOTP key and download a VPN file. Then there are some PHP vulnerable services that can be compromised and get to an internal server that contains a binary executable file having a Format String vulnerability. Deep knowledge about pivoting and port forwarding techniques, network enumeration and PHP exploitation, as well as Format String exploitation are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Ruby script to automate the process of downloading the VPN file, a Python script gain RCE over a PHP web server and another Python script to exploit a binary using Format String</description></item></channel></rss>