<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Backdoor on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/backdoor/</link><description>Recent content in Backdoor on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 02:13:27 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/backdoor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Undetected</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/undetected/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/undetected/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website in PHP with a third-party dependency that is vulnerable to RCE. The machine has already been compromised and has some backdoors and exploits that need to be detected and analyzed using reverse engineering techniques</description></item><item><title>Backdoor</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backdoor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backdoor/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a WordPress website that has a plugin vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal, which can be used to enumerate running processes, and then a SUID binary. WordPress enumeration and experience with file inclusion vulnerabilities is needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to read files from the server and a personal public exploit to gain access to the machine</description></item><item><title>Knife</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/knife/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/knife/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a webpage built on PHP with a version that has a backdoor and sudo permissions configured. Knowledge of the PHP version and basic privilege escalation skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Lame</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/lame/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/lame/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine exposes vulnerable versions for FTP and SMB services. The SMB service is exploitable and derives in RCE as root</description></item></channel></rss>