<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>password-reuse on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/password-reuse/</link><description>Recent content in password-reuse on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/password-reuse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GoodGames</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to SQL injection where we can extract a password to access an internal website that is vulnerable to SSTI. Then, we get access to a Docker container that mounts a directory from the machine, so that we can abuse it to escalate privileges. Basic web exploitation skills and Docker breakout techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Bolt</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has several virtual hosts and a Docker image that contains a lot of information needed to exploit the websites. There is an SSTI vulnerability between two websites interaction. Then we can extract a PGP private key from Google Chrome cache and decrypt a message. Deep knowledge about Docker and basic web exploitation skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>NodeBlog</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a blog that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection, then to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and finally to insecure deserialization to get Remote Code Execution. Advanced web pentesting techniques and scripting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses custom scripts in Bash, Python and Node.js to exploit all vulnerabilities</description></item><item><title>Writer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to SQL injection. This allows to read the source code of the server and find a vulnerability. Then some command injection techniques to escalate privileges. Some scripting for automating a SQLi exploit, SMB, SMTP and Cron tasks are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses custom Python scripts for SQLi and for the foothold</description></item><item><title>Union</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains Union-based SQL injection (SQLi) and command injection vulnerabilities. Some SQLi bypassing techniques and source code analysis skills are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Java program to automate a SQLi attack</description></item><item><title>BountyHunter</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bountyhunter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bountyhunter/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and that has sudo permissions configured. Some knowledge about XXE, PHP and Python is needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to read files from the server exploiting XXE</description></item><item><title>Cap</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/cap/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/cap/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains Insecure Direct Object Reference (IDOR) and system capabilities. Reading capture files in Wireshark and capabilities enumeration skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>