<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>password-reuse on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/password-reuse/</link><description>Recent content in password-reuse on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/password-reuse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Forgot</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forgot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forgot/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to password reset poisoning and web cache poisoning. Both vulnerabilities can be used to gain access with a normal account and then get the administrator&amp;rsquo;s cookie, respectively. After that, we can read a ticket with SSH credentials. Then, we can run a Machine Learning script as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> using &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, and there is a library with a vulnerable version where we can inject Python code to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Awkward</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/awkward/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/awkward/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website built in Vue.js that exposes a login form which can be easily bypassed. Then we find an API endpoint that tests connectivity of other websites, which can be exploited using Server-Side Request Forgery to find an internal API documentation. There we have some Node.js code to analyze and see how we can bypass some checks to obtain all the users information and crack a password hash. After that, we can log in, get a valid JWT token and crack it to find the secret. Therefore, we can forge any JWT token, which means we can inject any payload as token information. Using this power, we can read arbitrary files from the server exploiting &lt;code>awk&lt;/code> and find plaintext credentials inside a compressed archive. Next, we can access via SSH and find out another website built with PHP with two vulnerabilities. There is also a Cron task that takes information from a CSV file to send an email. The key here is to inject a malicious parameter in the CSV file so that the &lt;code>mail&lt;/code> command executes a malicious script, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Bagel</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bagel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bagel/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to Local File Read. With this, we can read the web application source code and see that there is a WebSocket server that uses C# .NET with a DLL to process the messages. We can download and reverse the DLL to read the C# source code. The program deserializes JSON data and there is a flaw that allows us to reuse a class of the codebase to read arbitrary files from the server. With this, we can read the private SSH key of a user, and then switch to another user with a password that is also stored in the DLL. This user is able to run &lt;code>dotnet&lt;/code> with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which can be used to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Shoppy</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection. Using this vulnerability, we can bypass authentication and list some hashed passwords that can be cracked. Then, we enumerate subdomains and find a MatterMost application in which we can access and find credentials for SSH in the machine. The first user is able to run a custom ELF binary that shows more credentials when using a specific master password. Finally, we can escalate privileges because the second user belongs to group docker</description></item><item><title>Health</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/health/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/health/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a webhook functionality that seems vulnerable to Server-Side Request Forgery. After trying some bypasses, we see that the SSRF attack can be performed using a redirection. Internally, there is an outdated Gogs version that is vulnerable to SQLi. Once found a payload to extract password hashes from the database, we can obtain and crack the hashes from the remote Gogs instance with SQLi through SSRF. Then, we can connect with SSH and find out that we can enter local paths in the database to read files from the server as root. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform the SSRF attack and another Go program to crack Gogs hashes</description></item><item><title>Shared</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shared/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shared/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has an e-commerce store that is vulnerable to SQLi. With this vulnerability we can get a hashed password which is reused for SSH. There is another user that runs ipython periodically, so we can inject a configuration file to execute commands. The second user is able to use a binary compiled in Go that connects to Redis. A binary analysis reveals the password, so we can connect to Redis and exploit a CVE to run Lua code, escape from the sandbox and execute system commands as root</description></item><item><title>Faculty</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/faculty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/faculty/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to SQLi and autentication bypass which leads to a website where we can export HTML content to PDF. There is a vulnerability where we can attach local files to the PDF file and read a password reused for SSH. Using sudo we can execute a Node.js script as another user and exploit a command injection vulnerability. This second user is allowed to run GDB and moreover GDB has cap_sys_ptrace capability set, so we can debug a process running as root and run arbitrary code</description></item><item><title>OpenSource</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/opensource/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/opensource/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website exposes its source code, being vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal. Using this vulnerability we can read the necessary files to compute the PIN for the Flask debug console and get Remote Code Execution in a Docker container. After that, we need to use port forwarding to view a Gitea instance and enter credentials found in a Git repository. Here we have the private SSH key so we can enter as a system user. There is a Cron job that commits new changes of a Git repository and leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Scanned</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/scanned/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/scanned/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine has a website that is able to analyze malware binaries. Analyzing the sandbox C code, we notice that we can use a log file to exfiltrate information through the web server report, and also abuse a misconfiguration to escape from chroot. Then, we can read a SQLite database file and extract a hashed password, which is reused for SSH. Once inside the machine, we are able to run a SUID binary from inside the sandbox and copy a malicious shared library so that the SUID binary runs Bash as root. Deep knowledge about Linux, programming in C and Bash, code audit experience and escaping techniques is needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script with an embedded C program to list directories and read files from the server and also a Go program to crack a hashed password</description></item><item><title>Talkative</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/talkative/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/talkative/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website that exposes a Jamovi application where we can get a reverse shell on a Docker container. Here we find some credentials for a Bolt CMS application, so we get administration access. From here we can modify a template by writing PHP code and get access to another container. This one has connectivity with port 22 of the machine, so we can get access to the machine via SSH reusing credentials. Then, we find that there&amp;rsquo;s another Docker container running MongoDB, which contains the database for a Rocket.Chat server. At this point, we can create a new account on Rocket.Chat and assign us administration role modifying the database entry. After that, we can set a new integration to gain RCE on the container that manages Rocket.Chat. Finally, this container has capability &lt;code>CAP_DAC_READ_SEARCH&lt;/code> enabled, which allows us to read files as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> from the host machine using an exploit. Moreover, the container is also vulnerable to another exploit to write arbitrary files as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> on the host machine</description></item><item><title>Catch</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine offers an APK file that contains hard-coded authentication tokens for some services exposed by the machine. One of the tokens can be used to enumerate a Let&amp;rsquo;s Chat application using its API and get credentials for Cachet. This service is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection in PHP and we can get more credentials to access via SSH. The machine has a Cron job configured to analyze APK files using a Bash script that is vulnerable to command injection, so we need to upload a maliciously crafted APK file to exploit it and become root</description></item><item><title>Paper</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/paper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/paper/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a WordPress website that has some secret information hidden in draft posts, and also a chat bot that shows sensitive information. After that, the server happens to be vulnerable to PolKit. WordPress enumeration is needed to compromise the machine</description></item><item><title>Pandora</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pandora/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pandora/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine exposes sensitive information through SNMP that allows to access the machine. Then we find a local instance of Pandora FMS that has multiple vulnerabilities and they can be exploited to gain RCE as another user. This user is allowed to run a SUID binary that is vulnerable to PATH hijacking, but the attack needs to be performed with an SSH shell. Basic enumeration and pentesting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Unicode</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses JWT tokens with JWKS and JKU that can be forged to arrive to a directory path traversal vulnerability that can be exploited using some Unicode bypassing. After that, there is a Python compiled binary that can be run with sudo and uses curl behind the hoods. Some JWT knowledge, path traversal and command injection bypassing techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to exploit a directory path traversal using JWT with JWKS</description></item><item><title>Backend</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backend/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/backend/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has an API where we can create a new account after some exploration. Then we can find some documentation in Swagger format where we see an endpoint to execute commands and to read files from the server. We must find the secret key used to sign JWT tokens in order to create a valid token to execute commands. Knowledge on JWT tokens and API enumeration are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Overflow</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Padding Oracle Attack and Bit Flipper Attack to login as admin and also vulnerable to SQLi by a CMS. There is another subdomain that runs a version of exiftool that has an RCE vulnerability. Once in the machine, lateral movements are relatively easy and privilege escalation consists of reversing and exploiting a Buffer Overflow vulnerability on a SUID binary. Deep knowledge on web exploitation, cryptography and binary exploitation are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform a Bit Flipper Attack and a Ruby script to exploit SQLi</description></item><item><title>Shibboleth</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shibboleth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shibboleth/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a vulnerable IPMI service where we can find a password that is reused for a Zabbix control panel. Here we can enter and get access to the machine. Next, we find a vulnerable version for MariaDB which leads to RCE as root. Good enumeration and pentesting methodology are needed in order to comprimise this machine</description></item><item><title>Ransom</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ransom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ransom/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a Laravel website with a login form that is vulnerable to Type Juggling. After that we find a encrypted ZIP file and we can perform a known plaintext attack to extract the files. The password expected for the login form is reused for the root user. Basic knowledge about web pentesting on PHP and knowledge about ZIP files is required in order to comprimise this machine</description></item><item><title>GoodGames</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to SQL injection where we can extract a password to access an internal website that is vulnerable to SSTI. Then, we get access to a Docker container that mounts a directory from the machine, so that we can abuse it to escalate privileges. Basic web exploitation skills and Docker breakout techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>Bolt</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has several virtual hosts and a Docker image that contains a lot of information needed to exploit the websites. There is an SSTI vulnerability between two websites interaction. Then we can extract a PGP private key from Google Chrome cache and decrypt a message. Deep knowledge about Docker and basic web exploitation skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>NodeBlog</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a blog that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection, then to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and finally to insecure deserialization to get Remote Code Execution. Advanced web pentesting techniques and scripting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses custom scripts in Bash, Python and Node.js to exploit all vulnerabilities</description></item><item><title>Writer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to SQL injection. This allows to read the source code of the server and find a vulnerability. Then some command injection techniques to escalate privileges. Some scripting for automating a SQLi exploit, SMB, SMTP and Cron tasks are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses custom Python scripts for SQLi and for the foothold</description></item><item><title>Union</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains Union-based SQL injection (SQLi) and command injection vulnerabilities. Some SQLi bypassing techniques and source code analysis skills are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Java program to automate a SQLi attack</description></item><item><title>BountyHunter</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bountyhunter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bountyhunter/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and that has sudo permissions configured. Some knowledge about XXE, PHP and Python is needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to read files from the server exploiting XXE</description></item><item><title>Cap</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/cap/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/cap/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains Insecure Direct Object Reference (IDOR) and system capabilities. Reading capture files in Wireshark and capabilities enumeration skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>