<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Volumes on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/volumes/</link><description>Recent content in Volumes on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:41:59 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/volumes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shoppy</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection. Using this vulnerability, we can bypass authentication and list some hashed passwords that can be cracked. Then, we enumerate subdomains and find a MatterMost application in which we can access and find credentials for SSH in the machine. The first user is able to run a custom ELF binary that shows more credentials when using a specific master password. Finally, we can escalate privileges because the second user belongs to group docker</description></item><item><title>Stacked</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/stacked/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/stacked/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine contains a LocalStack environment that is vulnerable to CSRF and command injection. By discovering an XSS vulnerability in a subdomain, we can use CSRF to exploit the command injection vulnerability and get RCE inside a container. After escalating privileges inside the container by restarting a service and entering a malicious command, we can interact with Docker from the host machine and create a malicious container from scratch that mounts the host file system into the container to get arbitrary file read and write. Web exploitation techniques and deep Docker knowledge is needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>GoodGames</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to SQL injection where we can extract a password to access an internal website that is vulnerable to SSTI. Then, we get access to a Docker container that mounts a directory from the machine, so that we can abuse it to escalate privileges. Basic web exploitation skills and Docker breakout techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>SteamCloud</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/steamcloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/steamcloud/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a Kubernetes cluster that exposes the kubelet and it is vulnerable to unauthenticated RCE. We are able to extract credentials from a running Pod and use them to create a malicious Pod that mounts the hosts file system. Basic knowledge about pentesting on Kubernetes is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Mirai</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/mirai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/mirai/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine is a Raspberry Pi device that is configured with default credentials, so we can access through SSH and become root because we belong to group sudo. To get the root.txt flag, we need to do a raw copy of a USB stick</description></item></channel></rss>