<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>file-permissions on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/file-permissions/</link><description>Recent content in file-permissions on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/file-permissions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Awkward</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/awkward/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/awkward/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website built in Vue.js that exposes a login form which can be easily bypassed. Then we find an API endpoint that tests connectivity of other websites, which can be exploited using Server-Side Request Forgery to find an internal API documentation. There we have some Node.js code to analyze and see how we can bypass some checks to obtain all the users information and crack a password hash. After that, we can log in, get a valid JWT token and crack it to find the secret. Therefore, we can forge any JWT token, which means we can inject any payload as token information. Using this power, we can read arbitrary files from the server exploiting &lt;code>awk&lt;/code> and find plaintext credentials inside a compressed archive. Next, we can access via SSH and find out another website built with PHP with two vulnerabilities. There is also a Cron task that takes information from a CSV file to send an email. The key here is to inject a malicious parameter in the CSV file so that the &lt;code>mail&lt;/code> command executes a malicious script, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>RainyDay</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rainyday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rainyday/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website vulnerable to user enumeration. Then we can use brute force a user&amp;rsquo;s password and run containers. Using a container we can access an internal website that has an API that shows sensitive information using Type Juggling and has a feature for matching regular expressions on given files, so that we can read source code and get the secret key for Flask. Then, we can forge a session for user &lt;code>jack&lt;/code> and find out that the Docker containers allow to access process information from the machine, and we can read the private SSH key of this user. Next, we can run a custom Python interpreter and escape the sandbox to get a shell as &lt;code>jack_adm&lt;/code>. Finally, we have a tool to generate hashes with &lt;code>bcrypt&lt;/code>, and we need to exploit a limitation of &lt;code>bcrypt&lt;/code> to extract a secret pepper string and then crack &lt;code>root&lt;/code>&amp;rsquo;s hash in order to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>UpDown</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/updown/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/updown/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that has a development directory and exposes a Git repository. Using this, we can find some functionality that is hidden except for developers and can be abused to get RCE after planning the attack and bypassing &lt;code>disable_functions&lt;/code> in PHP. In the machine, there&amp;rsquo;s a SUID binary compiled out of a Python script, which can be abused with a library hijacking attack. Finally, the developer user is able to run &lt;code>easy_install&lt;/code> with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Trick</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/trick/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/trick/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a DNS service that is vulnerable to a Domain Zone Transfer attack and leaks a subdomain. Here we can bypass authentication with SQLi and exploit an LFI. Both vulnerabilities can be chained to get access to the machine. Then, we find another subdomain that is again vulnerable to LFI, and we can leak a user&amp;rsquo;s SSH private key. This user is able to restart fail2ban with sudo and modify configuration files</description></item><item><title>Late</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/late/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/late/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a Flask web application that extracts text from images and renders them, being vulnerable to SSTI. Then there is a PAM configured for SSH with relative paths that can be abused because of some privileges to ovewrite executables. Basic web exploitation and Linux enumeration skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Acute</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/acute/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/acute/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Hard machine. This machine exposes a website where we can find a Word document with useful information and some usernames. There is a PowerShell Web Access where we can access using a default credential and extract another password from a screenshot. There is an Active Directory domain controller where we can execute commands as other users. We will be able to connect to the first machine and dump NTLM hashes and finally become domain administrator. Deep knowledge on PowerShell commands and basic Windows and Active Directory exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Overflow</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Padding Oracle Attack and Bit Flipper Attack to login as admin and also vulnerable to SQLi by a CMS. There is another subdomain that runs a version of exiftool that has an RCE vulnerability. Once in the machine, lateral movements are relatively easy and privilege escalation consists of reversing and exploiting a Buffer Overflow vulnerability on a SUID binary. Deep knowledge on web exploitation, cryptography and binary exploitation are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform a Bit Flipper Attack and a Ruby script to exploit SQLi</description></item><item><title>Writer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to SQL injection. This allows to read the source code of the server and find a vulnerability. Then some command injection techniques to escalate privileges. Some scripting for automating a SQLi exploit, SMB, SMTP and Cron tasks are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses custom Python scripts for SQLi and for the foothold</description></item><item><title>Seal</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a Tomcat website on top of nginx, which has a configuration vulnerability that leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE), then it has some misconfigurations related to file permissions and sudo commands. Knowledge about Tomcat exploitation and Linux file system is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Monitors</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a WordPress web site with a plugin vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal, another website vulnerable to SQL injection, and yet another webpage vulnerable to Insecure Deserialization running inside a Docker container with system capabilities enabled. Deep knowledge about web enumeration, vulnerabilities and exploitation techniques, as well as port forwarding and Docker escaping methods are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to exploit Insecure Deserialization</description></item><item><title>Rope</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine exposes a custom web server that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal so we can read files and discover that it is a binary file. After ananlyzing the binary, we discover that it has a Format String vulnerability that can be exploited to get RCE as john. This user is able to run another binary as user r4j. This binary uses an external library that we can modify because of its permissions and gain access as r4j. Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s another binary that runs a local socket server, we can access the binary and analyze it to find out a Buffer Overflow vulnerability. The binary has all protections set, but it is still exploitable to get RCE as root</description></item></channel></rss>