<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cve on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/cve/</link><description>Recent content in cve on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/cve/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Driver</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine contains a website with default credentials authentication and a file upload. Here we can upload an SCF to capture the user&amp;rsquo;s NTLMv2 hash and crack it. Then we can exploit PrintNightmare. Windows basic exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Horizontall</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/horizontall/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/horizontall/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that hides a valid subdomain that contains a Strapi webapp vulnerable to RCE. There is also an internal Laravel webapp vulnerable to RCE. Some knowledge about JavaScript, PHP and Python, as well as port forwarding techniques, are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom script that chains two exploits for Strapi needed to obtain RCE</description></item><item><title>NodeBlog</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a blog that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection, then to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and finally to insecure deserialization to get Remote Code Execution. Advanced web pentesting techniques and scripting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses custom scripts in Bash, Python and Node.js to exploit all vulnerabilities</description></item><item><title>Static</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/static/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/static/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that exposes a corrupted Gzip file that must be patched to get a TOTP key and download a VPN file. Then there are some PHP vulnerable services that can be compromised and get to an internal server that contains a binary executable file having a Format String vulnerability. Deep knowledge about pivoting and port forwarding techniques, network enumeration and PHP exploitation, as well as Format String exploitation are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Ruby script to automate the process of downloading the VPN file, a Python script gain RCE over a PHP web server and another Python script to exploit a binary using Format String</description></item><item><title>LogForge</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses Log4j in a Tomcat server that is vulnerable to JNDI lookup. Then there is an FTP server made in Java that also uses Log4j, but this time it is only vulnerable to information disclosure. Knowlegde about Log4j exploitation, Tomcat, FTP and Wireshark are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Explore</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/explore/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/explore/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Android. Easy machine. This is a mobile device that uses a vulnerable application that exposes files that provide access via SSH. Some port scanning, port forwarding and Android skills are needed to compromise this device</description></item><item><title>Monitors</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a Wordpress web site with a plugin vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal, another website vulnerable to SQL injection, and yet another webpage vulnerable to Insecure Deserialization running inside a Docker container with system capabilities enabled. Deep knowledge about web enumeration, vulnerabilities and exploitation techniques, as well as port forwarding and Docker escaping methods are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to exploit Insecure Deserialization</description></item><item><title>Antique</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/antique/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/antique/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine is a HP JetDirect printer that exposes its password through SNMP and has an arbritrary file read vulnerability. SNMP enumeration and port forwarding techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to obtain a clear-text password</description></item></channel></rss>