<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cve on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/cve/</link><description>Recent content in cve on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/cve/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pilgrimage</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pilgrimage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pilgrimage/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that exposes a Git repository. We are able to extract the PHP source of the web application and find out that it uses ImageMagick under the hood to process uploaded images. The version of ImageMagick has a local file read vulnerability that can be used to read a SQLite database file and find a plaintext password for &lt;code>emily&lt;/code>, which is used in SSH too. After that, we find that &lt;code>root&lt;/code> executes a Bash script that uses &lt;code>binwalk&lt;/code> to remove malware from uploaded image files. The version of &lt;code>binwalk&lt;/code> is vulnerable to Remote Code Execution, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>MonitorsTwo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitorstwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitorstwo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a Cacti service that is vulnerable to unauthenticated Remote Code Execution that grants access to a Docker container. Here we can find credentials in the database and reuse them for SSH on the host machine. Then, we find out that the Docker version is vulnerable to a CVE. To exploit this, we need to get &lt;code>root&lt;/code> in the container and configure a SUID binary that will be executed from the host machine via directory traversal to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Precious</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/precious/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/precious/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application that uses a tool to create PDF documents which is vulnerable to command injection, which leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE). Then, we can find plaintext credentials to switch to another user. And this user has &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code> permissions to run a Ruby script that is vulnerable to insecure deserialization in YAML, which can be used to execute commands as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>MetaTwo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/metatwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/metatwo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a WordPress website that uses a plugin that is vulnerable to SQLi. Then we can get password hashes and crack one of them to get access to the WordPress dashboard. The version of WordPress is vulnerable to out-of-band XXE using a WAV file that allows to read files from the server. Using this vulnerability, we can find plaintext credentials for FTP. In this service we have another PHP file with more plaintext credentials that are valid for SSH. Once inside the machine, we can see some PGP keys and messages that can be decrypted to find the password for &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Investigation</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/investigation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/investigation/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that allows to analyze image file metadata with &lt;code>exiftool&lt;/code>. However, the version is vulnerable to command injection and can be used to access the system. Then, we find some Windows event logs and a plaintext password as username, probably a mistake. After that, we gain access as another user that is able to execute a binary with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which behind the scenes runs a Perl script that leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Vessel</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/vessel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/vessel/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website that exposes a Git repository. Here we can read the source code of the web application and find out a way to bypass authentication in MySQL with Type Juggling. Then, we find another subdomain that has a public exploit to get RCE. After that, we discover a password generator tool that can be reverse-engineered to generate multiple passwords and crack a password-protected PDF document. Then, we get access via SSH and see that we can use &lt;code>sysctl&lt;/code> as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> with &lt;code>pinns&lt;/code> as SUID binary. With this, we can modify the kernel configuration to run an arbitrary script with a program crashes, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Forgot</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forgot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forgot/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to password reset poisoning and web cache poisoning. Both vulnerabilities can be used to gain access with a normal account and then get the administrator&amp;rsquo;s cookie, respectively. After that, we can read a ticket with SSH credentials. Then, we can run a Machine Learning script as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> using &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, and there is a library with a vulnerable version where we can inject Python code to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Ambassador</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ambassador/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ambassador/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a Grafana instance that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal without authentication. There, we can read files from the server and find the password for Grafana and for MySQL. After that, we can connect to MySQL, which is exposed, and find another password to access via SSH. The machine runs &lt;code>consul&lt;/code> internally with a vulnerable configuration. After finding an authentication token in a Git repository, we can use an exploit to get RCE from &lt;code>consul&lt;/code> and get access as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Health</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/health/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/health/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a webhook functionality that seems vulnerable to Server-Side Request Forgery. After trying some bypasses, we see that the SSRF attack can be performed using a redirection. Internally, there is an outdated Gogs version that is vulnerable to SQLi. Once found a payload to extract password hashes from the database, we can obtain and crack the hashes from the remote Gogs instance with SQLi through SSRF. Then, we can connect with SSH and find out that we can enter local paths in the database to read files from the server as root. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform the SSRF attack and another Go program to crack Gogs hashes</description></item><item><title>Shared</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shared/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shared/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has an e-commerce store that is vulnerable to SQLi. With this vulnerability we can get a hashed password which is reused for SSH. There is another user that runs ipython periodically, so we can inject a configuration file to execute commands. The second user is able to use a binary compiled in Go that connects to Redis. A binary analysis reveals the password, so we can connect to Redis and exploit a CVE to run Lua code, escape from the sandbox and execute system commands as root</description></item><item><title>Catch</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine offers an APK file that contains hard-coded authentication tokens for some services exposed by the machine. One of the tokens can be used to enumerate a Let&amp;rsquo;s Chat application using its API and get credentials for Cachet. This service is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection in PHP and we can get more credentials to access via SSH. The machine has a Cron job configured to analyze APK files using a Bash script that is vulnerable to command injection, so we need to upload a maliciously crafted APK file to exploit it and become root</description></item><item><title>RouterSpace</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/routerspace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/routerspace/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a downloadable APK file with a simple app. This app performs a web request to an API the needs th be captured with a proxy, and this API is vulnerable to a command injection. After that, we can access to the machine via SSH and basic enumeration shows that the version of sudo is vulnerable</description></item><item><title>Undetected</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/undetected/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/undetected/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website in PHP with a third-party dependency that is vulnerable to RCE. The machine has already been compromised and has some backdoors and exploits that need to be detected and analyzed using reverse engineering techniques</description></item><item><title>Paper</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/paper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/paper/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a WordPress website that has some secret information hidden in draft posts, and also a chat bot that shows sensitive information. After that, the server happens to be vulnerable to PolKit. WordPress enumeration is needed to compromise the machine</description></item><item><title>Meta</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/meta/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that analyzes uploaded images with a vulnerable version of exiftool that leads to RCE. Then, there is a Cron job that transforms images using ImageMagick&amp;rsquo;s mogrify command, which is vulnerable to command injection. Finally, we have sudo permissions on neofetch, which leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Pandora</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pandora/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pandora/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine exposes sensitive information through SNMP that allows to access the machine. Then we find a local instance of Pandora FMS that has multiple vulnerabilities and they can be exploited to gain RCE as another user. This user is allowed to run a SUID binary that is vulnerable to PATH hijacking, but the attack needs to be performed with an SSH shell. Basic enumeration and pentesting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Overflow</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Padding Oracle Attack and Bit Flipper Attack to login as admin and also vulnerable to SQLi by a CMS. There is another subdomain that runs a version of exiftool that has an RCE vulnerability. Once in the machine, lateral movements are relatively easy and privilege escalation consists of reversing and exploiting a Buffer Overflow vulnerability on a SUID binary. Deep knowledge on web exploitation, cryptography and binary exploitation are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform a Bit Flipper Attack and a Ruby script to exploit SQLi</description></item><item><title>Shibboleth</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shibboleth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shibboleth/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a vulnerable IPMI service where we can find a password that is reused for a Zabbix control panel. Here we can enter and get access to the machine. Next, we find a vulnerable version for MariaDB which leads to RCE as root. Good enumeration and pentesting methodology are needed in order to comprimise this machine</description></item><item><title>Altered</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/altered/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/altered/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a PHP website vulnerable to user enumeration. Then we can use brute force on a PIN to reset a password after bypassing rate limits and exploit SQLi and Type Juggling. After that, we see that the Linux kernel is vulnerable to DirtyPipe. Advanced web exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Ruby script to find the valid PIN</description></item><item><title>Stacked</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/stacked/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/stacked/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine contains a LocalStack environment that is vulnerable to CSRF and command injection. By discovering an XSS vulnerability in a subdomain, we can use CSRF to exploit the command injection vulnerability and get RCE inside a container. After escalating privileges inside the container by restarting a service and entering a malicious command, we can interact with Docker from the host machine and create a malicious container from scratch that mounts the host file system into the container to get arbitrary file read and write. Web exploitation techniques and deep Docker knowledge is needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Devzat</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/devzat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/devzat/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains chat service over SSH and a hidden web subdomain vulnerable to command injection. Then we can access the machine and exploit a vulnerable version of InluxDB to extract the password for another user. This user has permissions to see a development project for the SSH chat that allows to read arbitrary files from the server. Basic web exploitation and Linux enumeration techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Hancliffe</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/hancliffe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/hancliffe/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Hard machine. This machine contains a webpage that hides a Nuxeo Java application vulnerable to SSTI by breaking nginx parser logic. Then we find access the machine and find an application that has a public exploit to access as another user. After that, we extract Firefox credentials and use a password generator to login as another user and find a custom Windows PE. Having reversed the binary to obtain the expected credentials, we find a Buffer Overflow vulnerability that must be exploited via Socket Reuse to access as Administrator</description></item><item><title>Driver</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/driver/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine contains a website with default credentials authentication and a file upload. Here we can upload an SCF to capture the user&amp;rsquo;s NTLMv2 hash and crack it. Then we can exploit PrintNightmare. Windows basic exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Horizontall</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/horizontall/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/horizontall/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that hides a valid subdomain that contains a Strapi webapp vulnerable to RCE. There is also an internal Laravel webapp vulnerable to RCE. Some knowledge about JavaScript, PHP and Python, as well as port forwarding techniques, are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom script that chains two exploits for Strapi needed to obtain RCE</description></item><item><title>NodeBlog</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a blog that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection, then to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and finally to insecure deserialization to get Remote Code Execution. Advanced web pentesting techniques and scripting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses custom scripts in Bash, Python and Node.js to exploit all vulnerabilities</description></item><item><title>Static</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/static/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/static/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that exposes a corrupted Gzip file that must be patched to get a TOTP key and download a VPN file. Then there are some PHP vulnerable services that can be compromised and get to an internal server that contains a binary executable file having a Format String vulnerability. Deep knowledge about pivoting and port forwarding techniques, network enumeration and PHP exploitation, as well as Format String exploitation are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Ruby script to automate the process of downloading the VPN file, a Python script gain RCE over a PHP web server and another Python script to exploit a binary using Format String</description></item><item><title>LogForge</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses Log4j in a Tomcat server that is vulnerable to JNDI lookup. Then there is an FTP server made in Java that also uses Log4j, but this time it is only vulnerable to information disclosure. Knowlegde about Log4j exploitation, Tomcat, FTP and Wireshark are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Explore</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/explore/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/explore/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Android. Easy machine. This is a mobile device that uses a vulnerable application that exposes files that provide access via SSH. Some port scanning, port forwarding and Android skills are needed to compromise this device</description></item><item><title>Monitors</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a WordPress web site with a plugin vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal, another website vulnerable to SQL injection, and yet another webpage vulnerable to Insecure Deserialization running inside a Docker container with system capabilities enabled. Deep knowledge about web enumeration, vulnerabilities and exploitation techniques, as well as port forwarding and Docker escaping methods are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to exploit Insecure Deserialization</description></item><item><title>Antique</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/antique/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/antique/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine is a HP JetDirect printer that exposes its password through SNMP and has an arbritrary file read vulnerability. SNMP enumeration and port forwarding techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to obtain a clear-text password</description></item><item><title>Blue</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/blue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/blue/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine exposes SMB version 1, which is vulnerable to EternalBlue. Once the exploit is done, we get access as Administrator</description></item><item><title>Lame</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/lame/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/lame/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine exposes vulnerable versions for FTP and SMB services. The SMB service is exploitable and derives in RCE as root</description></item></channel></rss>