<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Library-Hijacking on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/library-hijacking/</link><description>Recent content in Library-Hijacking on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 18:56:03 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/library-hijacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sandworm</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sandworm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sandworm/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that allows to encrypt, decrypt and verify signatures using PGP. The website is vulnerable to SSTI in Flask, which is the way to access the machine as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code>. However, this environment is limited due to &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code>, but we are able to find a plaintext password to login as &lt;code>silentobserver&lt;/code> in SSH. As this user, we are able to modify a Rust project that is used in another Rust project that runs periodically as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code>. With this power, we can get access as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code> again, but outside &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code>. Finally, since &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code> is a SUID binary, we can use a public exploit to become &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>UpDown</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/updown/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/updown/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that has a development directory and exposes a Git repository. Using this, we can find some functionality that is hidden except for developers and can be abused to get RCE after planning the attack and bypassing &lt;code>disable_functions&lt;/code> in PHP. In the machine, there&amp;rsquo;s a SUID binary compiled out of a Python script, which can be abused with a library hijacking attack. Finally, the developer user is able to run &lt;code>easy_install&lt;/code> with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Scanned</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/scanned/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/scanned/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine has a website that is able to analyze malware binaries. Analyzing the sandbox C code, we notice that we can use a log file to exfiltrate information through the web server report, and also abuse a misconfiguration to escape from chroot. Then, we can read a SQLite database file and extract a hashed password, which is reused for SSH. Once inside the machine, we are able to run a SUID binary from inside the sandbox and copy a malicious shared library so that the SUID binary runs Bash as root. Deep knowledge about Linux, programming in C and Bash, code audit experience and escaping techniques is needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script with an embedded C program to list directories and read files from the server and also a Go program to crack a hashed password</description></item><item><title>Rope</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine exposes a custom web server that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal so we can read files and discover that it is a binary file. After ananlyzing the binary, we discover that it has a Format String vulnerability that can be exploited to get RCE as &lt;code>john&lt;/code>. This user is able to run another binary as user &lt;code>r4j&lt;/code>. This binary uses an external library that we can modify because of its permissions and gain access as &lt;code>r4j&lt;/code>. Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s another binary that runs a local socket server, we can access the binary and analyze it to find out a Buffer Overflow vulnerability. The binary has all protections set, but it is still exploitable to get RCE as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item></channel></rss>