<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>powershell on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/powershell/</link><description>Recent content in powershell on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Timelapse</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timelapse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timelapse/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Easy machine. This machine presents an Active Directory (AD) environment where we can find an encrypted ZIP file in SMB. We can crack the password and find a PFX file holding public and private keys for WinRM. Again we can crack the password and extract the keys to connect to the machine. There is a PowerShell history where we find a password for a LAPS reader member, which will tell us the password for Administrator. Basic Windows exploitation techniques and enumeration are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Acute</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/acute/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/acute/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Hard machine. This machine exposes a website where we can find a Word document with useful information and some usernames. There is a PowerShell Web Access where we can access using a default credential and extract another password from a screenshot. There is an Active Directory domain controller where we can execute commands as other users. We will be able to connect to the first machine and dump NTLM hashes and finally become domain administrator. Deep knowledge on PowerShell commands and basic Windows and Active Directory exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>