<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cronjob on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/cronjob/</link><description>Recent content in Cronjob on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 09:58:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/cronjob/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RegistryTwo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/registrytwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/registrytwo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine exposes a web application that allows to create custom domains with HTML code. Moreover, there is a Docker registry exposed where we can download Docker image blobs after getting a suitable JWT token. The web application is running a WAR file with Tomcat, we can decompile it and see that it queries a RMI server. Since Tomcat is behind an nginx reverse proxy, we can access some sensitive Tomcat &lt;em>servlets&lt;/em> to modify our session and set manager permissions on the web application. We need this to modify the RMI configuration using a mass assignment vulnerability and point the RMI server to us. After that, we can exploit an insecure deserialization vulnerability in Java to get RCE in a container. Then, we can interact with the legitimate RMI server using port forwarding. This server allows us to read arbitrary files with a directory traversal attack. We can find a plaintext password for user &lt;code>developer&lt;/code>, which is reused in SSH. Then, &lt;code>root&lt;/code> is executing a JAR file to analyze files of the hosting website by sending them to a ClamAV server. The problem here is that the JAR calls functions from the RMI register, which is restarted periodically. Therefore, we can craft a malicious RMI registry and exploit win a race condition to take the port, so that &lt;code>root&lt;/code> queries our malicious registry and talks to our fake ClamAV server. The result is that all files at &lt;code>/root&lt;/code> will be quarantined inside a readable directory, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Sandworm</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sandworm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sandworm/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that allows to encrypt, decrypt and verify signatures using PGP. The website is vulnerable to SSTI in Flask, which is the way to access the machine as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code>. However, this environment is limited due to &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code>, but we are able to find a plaintext password to login as &lt;code>silentobserver&lt;/code> in SSH. As this user, we are able to modify a Rust project that is used in another Rust project that runs periodically as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code>. With this power, we can get access as &lt;code>atlas&lt;/code> again, but outside &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code>. Finally, since &lt;code>firejail&lt;/code> is a SUID binary, we can use a public exploit to become &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Topology</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/topology/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/topology/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a website that allows to generate equations using LaTeX. With this feature we can read arbitrary files from the server with LaTeX injection techniques and find a hashed password for another subdomain, which can be cracked. This password is reused in SSH. After that, &lt;code>root&lt;/code> is executing &lt;code>gnuplot&lt;/code> scripts periodically, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Interface</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/interface/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/interface/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a dummy Next.js website that exposes a subdomain in the &lt;code>Content-Security-Policy&lt;/code> header. There, we can enumerate third-party dependencies like &lt;code>dompdf&lt;/code>. This one is vulnerable to Remote Code Execution. After a lot of enumeration to interact with &lt;code>dompdf&lt;/code>, we find a way to get a reverse shell on the system. Then, user &lt;code>root&lt;/code> executes a shell script each minute, and the script is vulnerable to command injection, which must be exploited by adding malicious metadata to a temporary file. By chaining these steps, we are able to get a reverse shell as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>BroScience</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/broscience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/broscience/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website with a Local File Read vulnerability that can be used to read PHP source code and find a way to activate a new account. Then, we can perform a deserialization attack in PHP to get RCE. After that, we find a hashed password in the database that can be cracked and it is reused in the system. Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s a Cron task running by &lt;code>root&lt;/code> to renew OpenSSL certificates and the script has a command injection vulnerability, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Awkward</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/awkward/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/awkward/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website built in Vue.js that exposes a login form which can be easily bypassed. Then we find an API endpoint that tests connectivity of other websites, which can be exploited using Server-Side Request Forgery to find an internal API documentation. There we have some Node.js code to analyze and see how we can bypass some checks to obtain all the users information and crack a password hash. After that, we can log in, get a valid JWT token and crack it to find the secret. Therefore, we can forge any JWT token, which means we can inject any payload as token information. Using this power, we can read arbitrary files from the server exploiting &lt;code>awk&lt;/code> and find plaintext credentials inside a compressed archive. Next, we can access via SSH and find out another website built with PHP with two vulnerabilities. There is also a Cron task that takes information from a CSV file to send an email. The key here is to inject a malicious parameter in the CSV file so that the &lt;code>mail&lt;/code> command executes a malicious script, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>RedPanda</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/redpanda/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/redpanda/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application built with Spring Boot that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection with a particular format. After that, in order to escalate privileges, we must analyze a Java program, enter some malicious metadata in a JPEG image, add an XML External Entity into a controlled XML file, break a log parser logic and finally wait for root to process the XML file and read its private SSH key</description></item><item><title>OpenSource</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/opensource/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/opensource/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website exposes its source code, being vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal. Using this vulnerability we can read the necessary files to compute the PIN for the Flask debug console and get Remote Code Execution in a Docker container. After that, we need to use port forwarding to view a Gitea instance and enter credentials found in a Git repository. Here we have the private SSH key so we can enter as a system user. There is a Cron job that commits new changes of a Git repository and leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Retired</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/retired/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/retired/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP website that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal. There we find a PHP file that expects a file to be uploaded in order to be passed to a local socket server. We are able to enumerate open processes and download the binary that runs the server and see that it is vulnerable to Buffer Overflow. Once exploited, we can pivot to another user using symbolic links. And then, we are allowed to add custom executable formats, which can be exploited to become root. Solid binary exploitation techniques and Linux concepts are required in order to compromise this machine. This write-up contains some custom Python exploits for the foothold part</description></item><item><title>Catch</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine offers an APK file that contains hard-coded authentication tokens for some services exposed by the machine. One of the tokens can be used to enumerate a Let&amp;rsquo;s Chat application using its API and get credentials for Cachet. This service is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection in PHP and we can get more credentials to access via SSH. The machine has a Cron job configured to analyze APK files using a Bash script that is vulnerable to command injection, so we need to upload a maliciously crafted APK file to exploit it and become root</description></item><item><title>Acute</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/acute/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/acute/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Hard machine. This machine exposes a website where we can find a Word document with useful information and some usernames. There is a PowerShell Web Access where we can access using a default credential and extract another password from a screenshot. There is an Active Directory domain controller where we can execute commands as other users. We will be able to connect to the first machine and dump NTLM hashes and finally become domain administrator. Deep knowledge on PowerShell commands and basic Windows and Active Directory exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Meta</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/meta/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that analyzes uploaded images with a vulnerable version of exiftool that leads to RCE. Then, there is a Cron job that transforms images using ImageMagick&amp;rsquo;s mogrify command, which is vulnerable to command injection. Finally, we have sudo permissions on neofetch, which leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Overflow</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Padding Oracle Attack and Bit Flipper Attack to login as admin and also vulnerable to SQLi by a CMS. There is another subdomain that runs a version of exiftool that has an RCE vulnerability. Once in the machine, lateral movements are relatively easy and privilege escalation consists of reversing and exploiting a Buffer Overflow vulnerability on a SUID binary. Deep knowledge on web exploitation, cryptography and binary exploitation are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform a Bit Flipper Attack and a Ruby script to exploit SQLi</description></item><item><title>Epsilon</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that exposes Git repository with secrets in old commits. There is a website that needs a valid JWT token in order to exploit an SSTI vulnerability. The secret for the JWT tokens is stored in an AWS Lambda function. Then, there is a Cron job that can be exploited using symlinks to gain arbitrary read. Knowledge about Git, JWT, SSTI and AWS Lambda, as well as Cron job exploitation, is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Writer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to SQL injection. This allows to read the source code of the server and find a vulnerability. Then some command injection techniques to escalate privileges. Some scripting for automating a SQLi exploit, SMB, SMTP and Cron tasks are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses custom Python scripts for SQLi and for the foothold</description></item><item><title>Pikaboo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine uses nginx and Apache web servers with a misconfiguration that derives in directory path traversal and afterwards in local file inclusion. There are credentials for FTP in LDAP and a Cron job that is vulnerable to command injection. Web enumeration, knowledge about nginx and LDAP, file inclusion techniques and command injection tricks are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item></channel></rss>