<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cronjob on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/cronjob/</link><description>Recent content in cronjob on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/cronjob/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Retired</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/retired/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/retired/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP website that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal. There we find a PHP file that expects a file to be uploaded in order to be passed to a local socket server. We are able to enumerate open processes and download the binary that runs the server and see that it is vulnerable to Buffer Overflow. Once exploited, we can pivot to another user using symbolic links. And then, we are allowed to add custom executable formats, which can be exploited to become root. Solid binary exploitation techniques and Linux concepts are required in order to compromise this machine. This write-up contains some custom Python exploits for the foothold part</description></item><item><title>Catch</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine offers an APK file that contains hard-coded authentication tokens for some services exposed by the machine. One of the tokens can be used to enumerate a Let&amp;rsquo;s Chat application using its API and get credentials for Cachet. This service is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection in PHP and we can get more credentials to access via SSH. The machine has a Cron job configured to analyze APK files using a Bash script that is vulnerable to command injection, so we need to upload a maliciously crafted APK file to exploit it and become root</description></item><item><title>Acute</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/acute/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/acute/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Hard machine. This machine exposes a website where we can find a Word document with useful information and some usernames. There is a PowerShell Web Access where we can access using a default credential and extract another password from a screenshot. There is an Active Directory domain controller where we can execute commands as other users. We will be able to connect to the first machine and dump NTLM hashes and finally become domain administrator. Deep knowledge on PowerShell commands and basic Windows and Active Directory exploitation techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Overflow</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Padding Oracle Attack and Bit Flipper Attack to login as admin and also vulnerable to SQLi by a CMS. There is another subdomain that runs a version of exiftool that has an RCE vulnerability. Once in the machine, lateral movements are relatively easy and privilege escalation consists of reversing and exploiting a Buffer Overflow vulnerability on a SUID binary. Deep knowledge on web exploitation, cryptography and binary exploitation are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform a Bit Flipper Attack and a Ruby script to exploit SQLi</description></item><item><title>Epsilon</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that exposes Git repository with secrets in old commits. There is a website that needs a valid JWT token in order to exploit an SSTI vulnerability. The secret for the JWT tokens is stored in an AWS Lambda function. Then, there is a Cron job that can be exploited using symlinks to gain arbitrary read. Knowledge about Git, JWT, SSTI and AWS Lambda, as well as Cron job exploitation, is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Writer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to SQL injection. This allows to read the source code of the server and find a vulnerability. Then some command injection techniques to escalate privileges. Some scripting for automating a SQLi exploit, SMB, SMTP and Cron tasks are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses custom Python scripts for SQLi and for the foothold</description></item><item><title>Pikaboo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pikaboo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine uses nginx and Apache web servers with a misconfiguration that derives in directory path traversal and afterwards in local file inclusion. There are credentials for FTP in LDAP and a Cron job that is vulnerable to command injection. Web enumeration, knowledge about nginx and LDAP, file inclusion techniques and command injection tricks are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item></channel></rss>