<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reversing on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/reversing/</link><description>Recent content in Reversing on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 18:56:03 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/reversing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RegistryTwo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/registrytwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/registrytwo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine exposes a web application that allows to create custom domains with HTML code. Moreover, there is a Docker registry exposed where we can download Docker image blobs after getting a suitable JWT token. The web application is running a WAR file with Tomcat, we can decompile it and see that it queries a RMI server. Since Tomcat is behind an nginx reverse proxy, we can access some sensitive Tomcat &lt;em>servlets&lt;/em> to modify our session and set manager permissions on the web application. We need this to modify the RMI configuration using a mass assignment vulnerability and point the RMI server to us. After that, we can exploit an insecure deserialization vulnerability in Java to get RCE in a container. Then, we can interact with the legitimate RMI server using port forwarding. This server allows us to read arbitrary files with a directory traversal attack. We can find a plaintext password for user &lt;code>developer&lt;/code>, which is reused in SSH. Then, &lt;code>root&lt;/code> is executing a JAR file to analyze files of the hosting website by sending them to a ClamAV server. The problem here is that the JAR calls functions from the RMI register, which is restarted periodically. Therefore, we can craft a malicious RMI registry and exploit win a race condition to take the port, so that &lt;code>root&lt;/code> queries our malicious registry and talks to our fake ClamAV server. The result is that all files at &lt;code>/root&lt;/code> will be quarantined inside a readable directory, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Bagel</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bagel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bagel/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to Local File Read. With this, we can read the web application source code and see that there is a WebSocket server that uses C# .NET with a DLL to process the messages. We can download and reverse the DLL to read the C# source code. The program deserializes JSON data and there is a flaw that allows us to reuse a class of the codebase to read arbitrary files from the server. With this, we can read the private SSH key of a user, and then switch to another user with a password that is also stored in the DLL. This user is able to run &lt;code>dotnet&lt;/code> with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which can be used to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Investigation</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/investigation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/investigation/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that allows to analyze image file metadata with &lt;code>exiftool&lt;/code>. However, the version is vulnerable to command injection and can be used to access the system. Then, we find some Windows event logs and a plaintext password as username, probably a mistake. After that, we gain access as another user that is able to execute a binary with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which behind the scenes runs a Perl script that leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Vessel</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/vessel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/vessel/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website that exposes a Git repository. Here we can read the source code of the web application and find out a way to bypass authentication in MySQL with Type Juggling. Then, we find another subdomain that has a public exploit to get RCE. After that, we discover a password generator tool that can be reverse-engineered to generate multiple passwords and crack a password-protected PDF document. Then, we get access via SSH and see that we can use &lt;code>sysctl&lt;/code> as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> with &lt;code>pinns&lt;/code> as SUID binary. With this, we can modify the kernel configuration to run an arbitrary script with a program crashes, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Shoppy</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection. Using this vulnerability, we can bypass authentication and list some hashed passwords that can be cracked. Then, we enumerate subdomains and find a MatterMost application in which we can access and find credentials for SSH in the machine. The first user is able to run a custom ELF binary that shows more credentials when using a specific master password. Finally, we can escalate privileges because the second user belongs to group docker</description></item><item><title>OverGraph</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overgraph/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overgraph/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Open Redirect, a web application built with AngularJS which is vulnerable to Client-Side Template Injection and XSS, and a GraphQL endpoint. We are able to register a new account bypassing an OTP code using a NoSQLi payload. Then, we can perform a CSRF attack abusing the Open Redirect to inject an XSS payload on the victim&amp;rsquo;s profile in order to get an adminToken stored in localStorage. After that, we are able to upload video files that are processed with ffmpeg, so we can exploit a Server-Side Request Forgery vulnerability to read files from the server. Eventually, we will access as a user to the machine and find a binary that is running as root. Having analyzed the binary, we can obtain a valid token to use the program and exploit a vulnerability to write arbitrary data at an arbitrary address, leading to RCE or write permissions as root</description></item><item><title>Catch</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine offers an APK file that contains hard-coded authentication tokens for some services exposed by the machine. One of the tokens can be used to enumerate a Let&amp;rsquo;s Chat application using its API and get credentials for Cachet. This service is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection in PHP and we can get more credentials to access via SSH. The machine has a Cron job configured to analyze APK files using a Bash script that is vulnerable to command injection, so we need to upload a maliciously crafted APK file to exploit it and become root</description></item><item><title>RouterSpace</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/routerspace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/routerspace/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a downloadable APK file with a simple app. This app performs a web request to an API the needs th be captured with a proxy, and this API is vulnerable to a command injection. After that, we can access to the machine via SSH and basic enumeration shows that the version of sudo is vulnerable</description></item><item><title>Undetected</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/undetected/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/undetected/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website in PHP with a third-party dependency that is vulnerable to RCE. The machine has already been compromised and has some backdoors and exploits that need to be detected and analyzed using reverse engineering techniques</description></item><item><title>Unicode</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses JWT tokens with JWKS and JKU that can be forged to arrive to a directory path traversal vulnerability that can be exploited using some Unicode bypassing. After that, there is a Python compiled binary that can be run with sudo and uses curl behind the hoods. Some JWT knowledge, path traversal and command injection bypassing techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to exploit a directory path traversal using JWT with JWKS</description></item><item><title>Overflow</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overflow/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Padding Oracle Attack and Bit Flipper Attack to login as admin and also vulnerable to SQLi by a CMS. There is another subdomain that runs a version of exiftool that has an RCE vulnerability. Once in the machine, lateral movements are relatively easy and privilege escalation consists of reversing and exploiting a Buffer Overflow vulnerability on a SUID binary. Deep knowledge on web exploitation, cryptography and binary exploitation are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform a Bit Flipper Attack and a Ruby script to exploit SQLi</description></item><item><title>Hancliffe</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/hancliffe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/hancliffe/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Windows. Hard machine. This machine contains a webpage that hides a Nuxeo Java application vulnerable to SSTI by breaking nginx parser logic. Then we find access the machine and find an application that has a public exploit to access as another user. After that, we extract Firefox credentials and use a password generator to login as another user and find a custom Windows PE. Having reversed the binary to obtain the expected credentials, we find a Buffer Overflow vulnerability that must be exploited via Socket Reuse to access as Administrator</description></item><item><title>Rope</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine exposes a custom web server that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal so we can read files and discover that it is a binary file. After ananlyzing the binary, we discover that it has a Format String vulnerability that can be exploited to get RCE as &lt;code>john&lt;/code>. This user is able to run another binary as user &lt;code>r4j&lt;/code>. This binary uses an external library that we can modify because of its permissions and gain access as &lt;code>r4j&lt;/code>. Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s another binary that runs a local socket server, we can access the binary and analyze it to find out a Buffer Overflow vulnerability. The binary has all protections set, but it is still exploitable to get RCE as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item></channel></rss>