<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Symlinks on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/symlinks/</link><description>Recent content in Symlinks on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:41:59 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/symlinks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Retired</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/retired/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/retired/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP website that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal. There we find a PHP file that expects a file to be uploaded in order to be passed to a local socket server. We are able to enumerate open processes and download the binary that runs the server and see that it is vulnerable to Buffer Overflow. Once exploited, we can pivot to another user using symbolic links. And then, we are allowed to add custom executable formats, which can be exploited to become root. Solid binary exploitation techniques and Linux concepts are required in order to compromise this machine. This write-up contains some custom Python exploits for the foothold part</description></item><item><title>Timing</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP web application that is vulnerable to user enumeration, LFI, Type Juggling and SQLi, apart from some other bugs and misconfigurations. After reading the PHP source code, we find a way to upload a PHP web shell and get RCE. After that, we find a password inside a Git repository and access via SSH. Then, we can run a JAR file using sudo that downloads files as root, and we can use a symlink to write an authorized SSH key for root</description></item><item><title>Epsilon</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that exposes Git repository with secrets in old commits. There is a website that needs a valid JWT token in order to exploit an SSTI vulnerability. The secret for the JWT tokens is stored in an AWS Lambda function. Then, there is a Cron job that can be exploited using symlinks to gain arbitrary read. Knowledge about Git, JWT, SSTI and AWS Lambda, as well as Cron job exploitation, is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Seal</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a Tomcat website on top of nginx, which has a configuration vulnerability that leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE), then it has some misconfigurations related to file permissions and sudo commands. Knowledge about Tomcat exploitation and Linux file system is needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>