<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>android on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/android/</link><description>Recent content in android on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Catch</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/catch/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine offers an APK file that contains hard-coded authentication tokens for some services exposed by the machine. One of the tokens can be used to enumerate a Let&amp;rsquo;s Chat application using its API and get credentials for Cachet. This service is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection in PHP and we can get more credentials to access via SSH. The machine has a Cron job configured to analyze APK files using a Bash script that is vulnerable to command injection, so we need to upload a maliciously crafted APK file to exploit it and become root</description></item><item><title>RouterSpace</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/routerspace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/routerspace/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a downloadable APK file with a simple app. This app performs a web request to an API the needs th be captured with a proxy, and this API is vulnerable to a command injection. After that, we can access to the machine via SSH and basic enumeration shows that the version of sudo is vulnerable</description></item><item><title>Explore</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/explore/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/explore/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Android. Easy machine. This is a mobile device that uses a vulnerable application that exposes files that provide access via SSH. Some port scanning, port forwarding and Android skills are needed to compromise this device</description></item></channel></rss>