<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>docker on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in docker on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shoppy</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine website that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection. Using this vulnerability, we can bypass authentication and list some hashed passwords that can be cracked. Then, we enumerate subdomains and find a MatterMost application in which we can access and find credentials for SSH in the machine. The first user is able to run a custom ELF binary that shows more credentials when using a specific master password. Finally, we can escalate privileges because the second user belongs to group docker</description></item><item><title>OpenSource</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/opensource/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/opensource/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website exposes its source code, being vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal. Using this vulnerability we can read the necessary files to compute the PIN for the Flask debug console and get Remote Code Execution in a Docker container. After that, we need to use port forwarding to view a Gitea instance and enter credentials found in a Git repository. Here we have the private SSH key so we can enter as a system user. There is a Cron job that commits new changes of a Git repository and leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Stacked</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/stacked/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/stacked/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine contains a LocalStack environment that is vulnerable to CSRF and command injection. By discovering an XSS vulnerability in a subdomain, we can use CSRF to exploit the command injection vulnerability and get RCE inside a container. After escalating privileges inside the container by restarting a service and entering a malicious command, we can interact with Docker from the host machine and create a malicious container from scratch that mounts the host file system into the container to get arbitrary file read and write. Web exploitation techniques and deep Docker knowledge is needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>GoodGames</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to SQL injection where we can extract a password to access an internal website that is vulnerable to SSTI. Then, we get access to a Docker container that mounts a directory from the machine, so that we can abuse it to escalate privileges. Basic web exploitation skills and Docker breakout techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>Bolt</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has several virtual hosts and a Docker image that contains a lot of information needed to exploit the websites. There is an SSTI vulnerability between two websites interaction. Then we can extract a PGP private key from Google Chrome cache and decrypt a message. Deep knowledge about Docker and basic web exploitation skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Monitors</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a Wordpress web site with a plugin vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal, another website vulnerable to SQL injection, and yet another webpage vulnerable to Insecure Deserialization running inside a Docker container with system capabilities enabled. Deep knowledge about web enumeration, vulnerabilities and exploitation techniques, as well as port forwarding and Docker escaping methods are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to exploit Insecure Deserialization</description></item></channel></rss>