<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sudo on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/sudo/</link><description>Recent content in sudo on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/sudo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Faculty</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/faculty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/faculty/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to SQLi and autentication bypass which leads to a website where we can export HTML content to PDF. There is a vulnerability where we can attach local files to the PDF file and read a password reused for SSH. Using sudo we can execute a Node.js script as another user and exploit a command injection vulnerability. This second user is allowed to run GDB and moreover GDB has cap_sys_ptrace capability set, so we can debug a process running as root and run arbitrary code</description></item><item><title>RouterSpace</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/routerspace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/routerspace/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a downloadable APK file with a simple app. This app performs a web request to an API the needs th be captured with a proxy, and this API is vulnerable to a command injection. After that, we can access to the machine via SSH and basic enumeration shows that the version of sudo is vulnerable</description></item><item><title>Paper</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/paper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/paper/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a Wordpress website that has some secret information hidden in draft posts, and also a chat bot that shows sensitive information. After that, the server happens to be vulnerable to PolKit. Wordpress enumeration is needed to compromise the machine</description></item><item><title>Meta</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/meta/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that analyzes uploaded images with a vulnerable version of exiftool that leads to RCE. Then, there is a Cron job that transforms images using ImageMagick&amp;rsquo;s mogrify command, which is vulnerable to command injection. Finally, we have sudo permissions on neofetch, which leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Timing</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP web application that is vulnerable to user enumeration, LFI, Type Juggling and SQLi, apart from some other bugs and misconfigurations. After reading the PHP source code, we find a way to upload a PHP web shell and get RCE. After that, we find a password inside a Git repository and access via SSH. Then, we can run a JAR file using sudo that downloads files as root, and we can use a symlink to write an authorized SSH key for root</description></item><item><title>Unicode</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses JWT tokens with JWKS and JKU that can be forged to arrive to a directory path traversal vulnerability that can be exploited using some Unicode bypassing. After that, there is a Python compiled binary that can be run with sudo and uses curl behind the hoods. Some JWT knowledge, path traversal and command injection bypassing techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to exploit a directory path traversal using JWT with JWKS</description></item><item><title>Forge</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forge/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a Server-Side Request Forgery (SSRF) vulnerability from a subdomain to an FTP server. After that, there are sudo permissions to run a Python script with a debugger. Basic web pentesting bypassing techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to exploit the SSRF</description></item><item><title>NodeBlog</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a blog that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection, then to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and finally to insecure deserialization to get Remote Code Execution. Advanced web pentesting techniques and scripting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses custom scripts in Bash, Python and Node.js to exploit all vulnerabilities</description></item><item><title>Previse</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a webpage vulnerable to command injection after bypassing redirects and managing to register a new account. After that, a hash must be cracked to login as a low privileged user and perform a PATH hijacking using sudo. Common web pentesting and Burp Suite skills, as well as common privilege escalation techniques are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a custom Go program to automate the foothold process</description></item><item><title>Union</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains Union-based SQL injection (SQLi) and command injection vulnerabilities. Some SQLi bypassing techniques and source code analysis skills are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Java program to automate a SQLi attack</description></item><item><title>BountyHunter</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bountyhunter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bountyhunter/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and that has sudo permissions configured. Some knowledge about XXE, PHP and Python is needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to read files from the server exploiting XXE</description></item><item><title>Seal</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a Tomcat website on top of nginx, which has a configuration vulnerability that leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE), then it has some misconfigurations related to file permissions and sudo commands. Knowledge about Tomcat exploitation and Linux file system is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>dynstr</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/dynstr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/dynstr/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses a dynamic DNS service vulnerable to command injection and then the machine has sudo permissions for a command that uses a wildard. DNS knowledge, command injection techniques and wildcard abusing skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Knife</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/knife/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/knife/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a webpage built on PHP with a version that has a backdoor and sudo permissions configured. Knowledge of the PHP version and basic privilege escalation skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Rope</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine exposes a custom web server that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal so we can read files and discover that it is a binary file. After ananlyzing the binary, we discover that it has a Format String vulnerability that can be exploited to get RCE as john. This user is able to run another binary as user r4j. This binary uses an external library that we can modify because of its permissions and gain access as r4j. Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s another binary that runs a local socket server, we can access the binary and analyze it to find out a Buffer Overflow vulnerability. The binary has all protections set, but it is still exploitable to get RCE as root</description></item><item><title>Mirai</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/mirai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/mirai/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine is a Raspberry Pi device that is configured with default credentials, so we can access through SSH and become root because we belong to group sudo. To get the root.txt flag, we need to do a raw copy of a USB stick</description></item></channel></rss>