<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sudo on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/sudo/</link><description>Recent content in Sudo on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 17:28:44 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/sudo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sau</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sau/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/sau/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a web application that is vulnerable to SSRF, which can be used to read the contents of an internal server, which is vulnerable to command injection. The two vulnerabilities can be chained to get RCE on the machine. The low-privileged user is able to run &lt;code>systemctl&lt;/code> as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> using &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which leads to the privilege escalation via the default pager &lt;code>less&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Stocker</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/stocker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/stocker/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection. Using this vulnerability, we can bypass authentication. Then, we have a feature to convert an HTML output into PDF, being able to perform a Server-Side XSS attack to read files from the server, such as source code. Then we find a plaintext password that is reused in SSH. Finally, a user is able to run Node.js scripts with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code> in a path that matches a wildcard. Bypassing this wildcard is needed to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Soccer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/soccer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/soccer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a Tiny File Manager application that allows us to upload and execute PHP, so we can obtain a reverse shell as &lt;code>www-data&lt;/code>. In the machine, we can read the configuration for nginx and find another subdomain. This one exposes a WebSocket server that is vulnerable to Boolean-based Blind SQLi. By exploiting SQLi, we can find plaintext credentials that are reused in SSH. Finally, the user is allowed to run &lt;code>dstat&lt;/code> as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> using &lt;code>doas&lt;/code>, and we are able to create a plugin to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Bagel</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bagel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bagel/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to Local File Read. With this, we can read the web application source code and see that there is a WebSocket server that uses C# .NET with a DLL to process the messages. We can download and reverse the DLL to read the C# source code. The program deserializes JSON data and there is a flaw that allows us to reuse a class of the codebase to read arbitrary files from the server. With this, we can read the private SSH key of a user, and then switch to another user with a password that is also stored in the DLL. This user is able to run &lt;code>dotnet&lt;/code> with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which can be used to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Precious</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/precious/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/precious/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application that uses a tool to create PDF documents which is vulnerable to command injection, which leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE). Then, we can find plaintext credentials to switch to another user. And this user has &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code> permissions to run a Ruby script that is vulnerable to insecure deserialization in YAML, which can be used to execute commands as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Investigation</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/investigation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/investigation/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that allows to analyze image file metadata with &lt;code>exiftool&lt;/code>. However, the version is vulnerable to command injection and can be used to access the system. Then, we find some Windows event logs and a plaintext password as username, probably a mistake. After that, we gain access as another user that is able to execute a binary with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which behind the scenes runs a Perl script that leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Forgot</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forgot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forgot/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to password reset poisoning and web cache poisoning. Both vulnerabilities can be used to gain access with a normal account and then get the administrator&amp;rsquo;s cookie, respectively. After that, we can read a ticket with SSH credentials. Then, we can run a Machine Learning script as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> using &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, and there is a library with a vulnerable version where we can inject Python code to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>RainyDay</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rainyday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rainyday/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website vulnerable to user enumeration. Then we can use brute force a user&amp;rsquo;s password and run containers. Using a container we can access an internal website that has an API that shows sensitive information using Type Juggling and has a feature for matching regular expressions on given files, so that we can read source code and get the secret key for Flask. Then, we can forge a session for user &lt;code>jack&lt;/code> and find out that the Docker containers allow to access process information from the machine, and we can read the private SSH key of this user. Next, we can run a custom Python interpreter and escape the sandbox to get a shell as &lt;code>jack_adm&lt;/code>. Finally, we have a tool to generate hashes with &lt;code>bcrypt&lt;/code>, and we need to exploit a limitation of &lt;code>bcrypt&lt;/code> to extract a secret pepper string and then crack &lt;code>root&lt;/code>&amp;rsquo;s hash in order to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Photobomb</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/photobomb/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/photobomb/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application built with Sinatra that is vulnerable to command injection, which leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE). The user has &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code> permissions to run a Bash script that is vulnerable to &lt;code>PATH&lt;/code> hijacking, which can be used to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>UpDown</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/updown/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/updown/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that has a development directory and exposes a Git repository. Using this, we can find some functionality that is hidden except for developers and can be abused to get RCE after planning the attack and bypassing &lt;code>disable_functions&lt;/code> in PHP. In the machine, there&amp;rsquo;s a SUID binary compiled out of a Python script, which can be abused with a library hijacking attack. Finally, the developer user is able to run &lt;code>easy_install&lt;/code> with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Shoppy</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection. Using this vulnerability, we can bypass authentication and list some hashed passwords that can be cracked. Then, we enumerate subdomains and find a MatterMost application in which we can access and find credentials for SSH in the machine. The first user is able to run a custom ELF binary that shows more credentials when using a specific master password. Finally, we can escalate privileges because the second user belongs to group docker</description></item><item><title>Trick</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/trick/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/trick/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a DNS service that is vulnerable to a Domain Zone Transfer attack and leaks a subdomain. Here we can bypass authentication with SQLi and exploit an LFI. Both vulnerabilities can be chained to get access to the machine. Then, we find another subdomain that is again vulnerable to LFI, and we can leak a user&amp;rsquo;s SSH private key. This user is able to restart fail2ban with sudo and modify configuration files</description></item><item><title>Faculty</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/faculty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/faculty/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to SQLi and autentication bypass which leads to a website where we can export HTML content to PDF. There is a vulnerability where we can attach local files to the PDF file and read a password reused for SSH. Using sudo we can execute a Node.js script as another user and exploit a command injection vulnerability. This second user is allowed to run GDB and moreover GDB has cap_sys_ptrace capability set, so we can debug a process running as root and run arbitrary code</description></item><item><title>RouterSpace</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/routerspace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/routerspace/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a downloadable APK file with a simple app. This app performs a web request to an API the needs th be captured with a proxy, and this API is vulnerable to a command injection. After that, we can access to the machine via SSH and basic enumeration shows that the version of sudo is vulnerable</description></item><item><title>Paper</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/paper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/paper/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a WordPress website that has some secret information hidden in draft posts, and also a chat bot that shows sensitive information. After that, the server happens to be vulnerable to PolKit. WordPress enumeration is needed to compromise the machine</description></item><item><title>Meta</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/meta/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that analyzes uploaded images with a vulnerable version of exiftool that leads to RCE. Then, there is a Cron job that transforms images using ImageMagick&amp;rsquo;s mogrify command, which is vulnerable to command injection. Finally, we have sudo permissions on neofetch, which leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Timing</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP web application that is vulnerable to user enumeration, LFI, Type Juggling and SQLi, apart from some other bugs and misconfigurations. After reading the PHP source code, we find a way to upload a PHP web shell and get RCE. After that, we find a password inside a Git repository and access via SSH. Then, we can run a JAR file using sudo that downloads files as root, and we can use a symlink to write an authorized SSH key for root</description></item><item><title>Unicode</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses JWT tokens with JWKS and JKU that can be forged to arrive to a directory path traversal vulnerability that can be exploited using some Unicode bypassing. After that, there is a Python compiled binary that can be run with sudo and uses curl behind the hoods. Some JWT knowledge, path traversal and command injection bypassing techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to exploit a directory path traversal using JWT with JWKS</description></item><item><title>Forge</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/forge/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a Server-Side Request Forgery (SSRF) vulnerability from a subdomain to an FTP server. After that, there are sudo permissions to run a Python script with a debugger. Basic web pentesting bypassing techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to exploit the SSRF</description></item><item><title>NodeBlog</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a blog that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection, then to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and finally to insecure deserialization to get Remote Code Execution. Advanced web pentesting techniques and scripting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses custom scripts in Bash, Python and Node.js to exploit all vulnerabilities</description></item><item><title>Previse</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/previse/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a webpage vulnerable to command injection after bypassing redirects and managing to register a new account. After that, a hash must be cracked to login as a low privileged user and perform a PATH hijacking using sudo. Common web pentesting and Burp Suite skills, as well as common privilege escalation techniques are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a custom Go program to automate the foothold process</description></item><item><title>Union</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/union/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains Union-based SQL injection (SQLi) and command injection vulnerabilities. Some SQLi bypassing techniques and source code analysis skills are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Java program to automate a SQLi attack</description></item><item><title>BountyHunter</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bountyhunter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bountyhunter/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and that has sudo permissions configured. Some knowledge about XXE, PHP and Python is needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to read files from the server exploiting XXE</description></item><item><title>Seal</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a Tomcat website on top of nginx, which has a configuration vulnerability that leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE), then it has some misconfigurations related to file permissions and sudo commands. Knowledge about Tomcat exploitation and Linux file system is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>dynstr</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/dynstr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/dynstr/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses a dynamic DNS service vulnerable to command injection and then the machine has sudo permissions for a command that uses a wildard. DNS knowledge, command injection techniques and wildcard abusing skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Knife</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/knife/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/knife/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a webpage built on PHP with a version that has a backdoor and sudo permissions configured. Knowledge of the PHP version and basic privilege escalation skills are needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Rope</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/rope/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine exposes a custom web server that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal so we can read files and discover that it is a binary file. After ananlyzing the binary, we discover that it has a Format String vulnerability that can be exploited to get RCE as &lt;code>john&lt;/code>. This user is able to run another binary as user &lt;code>r4j&lt;/code>. This binary uses an external library that we can modify because of its permissions and gain access as &lt;code>r4j&lt;/code>. Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s another binary that runs a local socket server, we can access the binary and analyze it to find out a Buffer Overflow vulnerability. The binary has all protections set, but it is still exploitable to get RCE as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Mirai</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/mirai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/mirai/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine is a Raspberry Pi device that is configured with default credentials, so we can access through SSH and become root because we belong to group sudo. To get the root.txt flag, we need to do a raw copy of a USB stick</description></item></channel></rss>