<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Git on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/git/</link><description>Recent content in Git on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 16:34:16 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pilgrimage</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pilgrimage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pilgrimage/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that exposes a Git repository. We are able to extract the PHP source of the web application and find out that it uses ImageMagick under the hood to process uploaded images. The version of ImageMagick has a local file read vulnerability that can be used to read a SQLite database file and find a plaintext password for &lt;code>emily&lt;/code>, which is used in SSH too. After that, we find that &lt;code>root&lt;/code> executes a Bash script that uses &lt;code>binwalk&lt;/code> to remove malware from uploaded image files. The version of &lt;code>binwalk&lt;/code> is vulnerable to Remote Code Execution, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/intentions/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website with an API that is vulnerable to second-order SQLi. Then, there is an authentication mechanism that just requires the password hash, so we can take a hash from the dumped database and log in as an administrator. Then, there is a vulnerability involving PHP and ImageMagick that leads to RCE. Once in the machine, we can pivot to user &lt;code>greg&lt;/code> by analyzing a Git repository and finding plaintext credentials. After that, we are allowed to run a custom binary that hashes a given length of a file and compares the result with a set of pre-computed MD5 hashes. This binary has a capability that allows to read files as &lt;code>root&lt;/code>, which can be used to extract all the contents of any file after automating the process, which allows to read an SSH private key for &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>Vessel</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/vessel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/vessel/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a website that exposes a Git repository. Here we can read the source code of the web application and find out a way to bypass authentication in MySQL with Type Juggling. Then, we find another subdomain that has a public exploit to get RCE. After that, we discover a password generator tool that can be reverse-engineered to generate multiple passwords and crack a password-protected PDF document. Then, we get access via SSH and see that we can use &lt;code>sysctl&lt;/code> as &lt;code>root&lt;/code> with &lt;code>pinns&lt;/code> as SUID binary. With this, we can modify the kernel configuration to run an arbitrary script with a program crashes, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Ambassador</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ambassador/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/ambassador/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a Grafana instance that is vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal without authentication. There, we can read files from the server and find the password for Grafana and for MySQL. After that, we can connect to MySQL, which is exposed, and find another password to access via SSH. The machine runs &lt;code>consul&lt;/code> internally with a vulnerable configuration. After finding an authentication token in a Git repository, we can use an exploit to get RCE from &lt;code>consul&lt;/code> and get access as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>UpDown</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/updown/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/updown/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website that has a development directory and exposes a Git repository. Using this, we can find some functionality that is hidden except for developers and can be abused to get RCE after planning the attack and bypassing &lt;code>disable_functions&lt;/code> in PHP. In the machine, there&amp;rsquo;s a SUID binary compiled out of a Python script, which can be abused with a library hijacking attack. Finally, the developer user is able to run &lt;code>easy_install&lt;/code> with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Health</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/health/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/health/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a webhook functionality that seems vulnerable to Server-Side Request Forgery. After trying some bypasses, we see that the SSRF attack can be performed using a redirection. Internally, there is an outdated Gogs version that is vulnerable to SQLi. Once found a payload to extract password hashes from the database, we can obtain and crack the hashes from the remote Gogs instance with SQLi through SSRF. Then, we can connect with SSH and find out that we can enter local paths in the database to read files from the server as root. This write-up uses a custom Python script to perform the SSRF attack and another Go program to crack Gogs hashes</description></item><item><title>OpenSource</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/opensource/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/opensource/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website exposes its source code, being vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal. Using this vulnerability we can read the necessary files to compute the PIN for the Flask debug console and get Remote Code Execution in a Docker container. After that, we need to use port forwarding to view a Gitea instance and enter credentials found in a Git repository. Here we have the private SSH key so we can enter as a system user. There is a Cron job that commits new changes of a Git repository and leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Timing</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/timing/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a PHP web application that is vulnerable to user enumeration, LFI, Type Juggling and SQLi, apart from some other bugs and misconfigurations. After reading the PHP source code, we find a way to upload a PHP web shell and get RCE. After that, we find a password inside a Git repository and access via SSH. Then, we can run a JAR file using sudo that downloads files as root, and we can use a symlink to write an authorized SSH key for root</description></item><item><title>Secret</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy Machine. This machine contains an API that uses JWT tokens for authentication. We can download the proyect and discover that it is a Git repository, so that we can see the secret key in previous commits and exploit a command injection vulnerability. There is a SUID binary that reads files as root although it only shows some statistics of the file, but we are able to kill the process and read the coredump. Web exploitation techniques, Git enumeration and knowledge about Linux processes are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Epsilon</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that exposes Git repository with secrets in old commits. There is a website that needs a valid JWT token in order to exploit an SSTI vulnerability. The secret for the JWT tokens is stored in an AWS Lambda function. Then, there is a Cron job that can be exploited using symlinks to gain arbitrary read. Knowledge about Git, JWT, SSTI and AWS Lambda, as well as Cron job exploitation, is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Seal</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a Tomcat website on top of nginx, which has a configuration vulnerability that leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE), then it has some misconfigurations related to file permissions and sudo commands. Knowledge about Tomcat exploitation and Linux file system is needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>