<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>git on 7Rocky</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/git/</link><description>Recent content in git on 7Rocky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Secret</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/secret/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy Machine. This machine contains an API that uses JWT tokens for authentication. We can download the proyect and discover that it is a Git repository, so that we can see the secret key in previous commits and exploit a command injection vulnerability. There is a SUID binary that reads files as root although it only shows some statistics of the file, but we are able to kill the process and read the coredump. Web exploitation techniques, Git enumeration and knowledge about Linux processes are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Epsilon</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/epsilon/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that exposes Git repository with secrets in old commits. There is a website that needs a valid JWT token in order to exploit an SSTI vulnerability. The secret for the JWT tokens is stored in an AWS Lambda function. Then, there is a Cron job that can be exploited using symlinks to gain arbitrary read. Knowledge about Git, JWT, SSTI and AWS Lambda, as well as Cron job exploitation, is needed to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Seal</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/seal/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a Tomcat website on top of nginx, which has a configuration vulnerability that leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE), then it has some misconfigurations related to file permissions and sudo commands. Knowledge about Tomcat exploitation and Linux file system is needed to compromise this machine</description></item></channel></rss>