<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nosqli on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/nosqli/</link><description>Recent content in Nosqli on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 09:25:25 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/nosqli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stocker</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/stocker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/stocker/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection. Using this vulnerability, we can bypass authentication. Then, we have a feature to convert an HTML output into PDF, being able to perform a Server-Side XSS attack to read files from the server, such as source code. Then we find a plaintext password that is reused in SSH. Finally, a user is able to run Node.js scripts with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code> in a path that matches a wildcard. Bypassing this wildcard is needed to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Shoppy</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/shoppy/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a website that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection. Using this vulnerability, we can bypass authentication and list some hashed passwords that can be cracked. Then, we enumerate subdomains and find a MatterMost application in which we can access and find credentials for SSH in the machine. The first user is able to run a custom ELF binary that shows more credentials when using a specific master password. Finally, we can escalate privileges because the second user belongs to group docker</description></item><item><title>OverGraph</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overgraph/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/overgraph/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Open Redirect, a web application built with AngularJS which is vulnerable to Client-Side Template Injection and XSS, and a GraphQL endpoint. We are able to register a new account bypassing an OTP code using a NoSQLi payload. Then, we can perform a CSRF attack abusing the Open Redirect to inject an XSS payload on the victim&amp;rsquo;s profile in order to get an adminToken stored in localStorage. After that, we are able to upload video files that are processed with ffmpeg, so we can exploit a Server-Side Request Forgery vulnerability to read files from the server. Eventually, we will access as a user to the machine and find a binary that is running as root. Having analyzed the binary, we can obtain a valid token to use the program and exploit a vulnerability to write arbitrary data at an arbitrary address, leading to RCE or write permissions as root</description></item><item><title>NodeBlog</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a blog that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection, then to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and finally to insecure deserialization to get Remote Code Execution. Advanced web pentesting techniques and scripting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses custom scripts in Bash, Python and Node.js to exploit all vulnerabilities</description></item></channel></rss>