<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Insecure-Deserialization on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/insecure-deserialization/</link><description>Recent content in Insecure-Deserialization on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 12:36:13 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/insecure-deserialization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bizness</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bizness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bizness/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has a vulnerable version ofApache OFBiz that can be exploited to get RCE using an authentication bypass and Java deserialization payload. Once on the machine, we can inspect the database and search for the password hash of the administrator user. Once the hash is cracked, we can reuse the password and gain access as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>RegistryTwo</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/registrytwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/registrytwo/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Insane machine. This machine exposes a web application that allows to create custom domains with HTML code. Moreover, there is a Docker registry exposed where we can download Docker image blobs after getting a suitable JWT token. The web application is running a WAR file with Tomcat, we can decompile it and see that it queries a RMI server. Since Tomcat is behind an nginx reverse proxy, we can access some sensitive Tomcat &lt;em>servlets&lt;/em> to modify our session and set manager permissions on the web application. We need this to modify the RMI configuration using a mass assignment vulnerability and point the RMI server to us. After that, we can exploit an insecure deserialization vulnerability in Java to get RCE in a container. Then, we can interact with the legitimate RMI server using port forwarding. This server allows us to read arbitrary files with a directory traversal attack. We can find a plaintext password for user &lt;code>developer&lt;/code>, which is reused in SSH. Then, &lt;code>root&lt;/code> is executing a JAR file to analyze files of the hosting website by sending them to a ClamAV server. The problem here is that the JAR calls functions from the RMI register, which is restarted periodically. Therefore, we can craft a malicious RMI registry and exploit win a race condition to take the port, so that &lt;code>root&lt;/code> queries our malicious registry and talks to our fake ClamAV server. The result is that all files at &lt;code>/root&lt;/code> will be quarantined inside a readable directory, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Bagel</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bagel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bagel/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to Local File Read. With this, we can read the web application source code and see that there is a WebSocket server that uses C# .NET with a DLL to process the messages. We can download and reverse the DLL to read the C# source code. The program deserializes JSON data and there is a flaw that allows us to reuse a class of the codebase to read arbitrary files from the server. With this, we can read the private SSH key of a user, and then switch to another user with a password that is also stored in the DLL. This user is able to run &lt;code>dotnet&lt;/code> with &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code>, which can be used to escalate privileges</description></item><item><title>Precious</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/precious/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/precious/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a web application that uses a tool to create PDF documents which is vulnerable to command injection, which leads to Remote Code Execution (RCE). Then, we can find plaintext credentials to switch to another user. And this user has &lt;code>sudo&lt;/code> permissions to run a Ruby script that is vulnerable to insecure deserialization in YAML, which can be used to execute commands as &lt;code>root&lt;/code></description></item><item><title>BroScience</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/broscience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/broscience/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a website with a Local File Read vulnerability that can be used to read PHP source code and find a way to activate a new account. Then, we can perform a deserialization attack in PHP to get RCE. After that, we find a hashed password in the database that can be cracked and it is reused in the system. Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s a Cron task running by &lt;code>root&lt;/code> to renew OpenSSL certificates and the script has a command injection vulnerability, which leads to the privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Pandora</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pandora/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/pandora/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine exposes sensitive information through SNMP that allows to access the machine. Then we find a local instance of Pandora FMS that has multiple vulnerabilities and they can be exploited to gain RCE as another user. This user is allowed to run a SUID binary that is vulnerable to PATH hijacking, but the attack needs to be performed with an SSH shell. Basic enumeration and pentesting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>NodeBlog</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/nodeblog/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a blog that is vulnerable to NoSQL injection, then to XML External Entity (XXE) injection and finally to insecure deserialization to get Remote Code Execution. Advanced web pentesting techniques and scripting skills are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses custom scripts in Bash, Python and Node.js to exploit all vulnerabilities</description></item><item><title>LogForge</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/logforge/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses Log4j in a Tomcat server that is vulnerable to JNDI lookup. Then there is an FTP server made in Java that also uses Log4j, but this time it is only vulnerable to information disclosure. Knowlegde about Log4j exploitation, Tomcat, FTP and Wireshark are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Monitors</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/monitors/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine has a WordPress web site with a plugin vulnerable to Directory Path Traversal, another website vulnerable to SQL injection, and yet another webpage vulnerable to Insecure Deserialization running inside a Docker container with system capabilities enabled. Deep knowledge about web enumeration, vulnerabilities and exploitation techniques, as well as port forwarding and Docker escaping methods are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Bash script to exploit Insecure Deserialization</description></item></channel></rss>