<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>flask on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/flask/</link><description>Recent content in flask on 7Rocky's Blog. Cybersecurity and Maths</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://7rocky.github.io/en/tags/flask/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Noter</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/noter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/noter/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has a web application built with Flask to manage notes in Markdown and PDF. We are able to extract the secret key used to sign session cookies and then forge cookies to enumerate users. Once we have a privileged user, we can access the FTP server and analyze the source code of the web application to detect a command injection vulnerability. Then, we can access the machine and find out that MySQL runs as root, which leads to privilege escalation</description></item><item><title>Late</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/late/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/late/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine contains a Flask web application that extracts text from images and renders them, being vulnerable to SSTI. Then there is a PAM configured for SSH with relative paths that can be abused because of some privileges to ovewrite executables. Basic web exploitation and Linux enumeration skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Unicode</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/unicode/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine uses JWT tokens with JWKS and JKU that can be forged to arrive to a directory path traversal vulnerability that can be exploited using some Unicode bypassing. After that, there is a Python compiled binary that can be run with sudo and uses curl behind the hoods. Some JWT knowledge, path traversal and command injection bypassing techniques are needed to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to exploit a directory path traversal using JWT with JWKS</description></item><item><title>GoodGames</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/goodgames/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Easy machine. This machine has website that is vulnerable to SQL injection where we can extract a password to access an internal website that is vulnerable to SSTI. Then, we get access to a Docker container that mounts a directory from the machine, so that we can abuse it to escalate privileges. Basic web exploitation skills and Docker breakout techniques are needed in order to compromise this machine. This write-up uses a custom Python script to compromise the entire machine from scratch</description></item><item><title>Bolt</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/bolt/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine has several virtual hosts and a Docker image that contains a lot of information needed to exploit the websites. There is an SSTI vulnerability between two websites interaction. Then we can extract a PGP private key from Google Chrome cache and decrypt a message. Deep knowledge about Docker and basic web exploitation skills are needed in order to compromise this machine</description></item><item><title>Writer</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/writer/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Medium machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to SQL injection. This allows to read the source code of the server and find a vulnerability. Then some command injection techniques to escalate privileges. Some scripting for automating a SQLi exploit, SMB, SMTP and Cron tasks are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses custom Python scripts for SQLi and for the foothold</description></item><item><title>Spider</title><link>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://7rocky.github.io/en/htb/spider/</guid><description>Hack The Box. Linux. Hard machine. This machine contains a website that is vulnerable to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI) in two fields and SQL injection (SQLi), and an internal website that is vulnerable to XML External Entity (XXE) injection. Advanced knowledge on SSTI and bypassing techniques, SQLi, XXE and port forwarding skills are needed to compromise the machine. This write-up uses a Python script to exploit SSTI and a Bash script to read file using XXE</description></item></channel></rss>